<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chris Beeley&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chris Beeley&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 16:12:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ai in  data science job applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2025-04-11-ai-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 16:12:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2025-04-11-ai-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a couple of times about people using AI to apply for jobs in my team. I don&amp;rsquo;t entirely feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve got my point across so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a blog post about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think sometimes people think that I actively want to weed out people who need AI to help them write an application form. So I&amp;rsquo;d like to say upfront that I do not want to weed out that kind of person. When I recruit data scientists I look for people who can communicate well, but that absolutely includes people who use AI to help them communicate well. Clearly you can use AI to communicate in the actual job, so I have no issue with people using it as part of the recruitment process. For the same reason I don&amp;rsquo;t give people silly tests they do in 30 minutes with no google in my interviews. I ask people to bring me some code they wrote and to talk about it. Use whatever tools you want, but bring me something that&amp;rsquo;s yours and explain it to me. And it works very well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valuing thought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2025-03-16-value-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:02:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2025-03-16-value-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think I already learned the lesson that is the subject of this blog post before but I&amp;rsquo;m having to relearn it in my new role as a data science manager rather than a data science do-er.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I first started to get into data science I made the mistake I think a lot of people make where they think &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m doing data science, data science is typing code, I want to do lots of data science, let&amp;rsquo;s type a lot of code&amp;rdquo;. And you just feverishly type code all day. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve been doing that for a few months you start to realise that you&amp;rsquo;re just making a huge mess. All your code needs refactoring, your dashboard is ugly and makes no sense, you&amp;rsquo;re using a model that really just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with the data. You make a big pile of mess at high speed and then slowly improve it at low speed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application form advice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-10-14-application-form-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 20:02:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-10-14-application-form-advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, so I&amp;rsquo;ve finished interviewing lots of data scientists over the last few weeks. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry that there were so many applications for the data scientist (hundreds) that I really can&amp;rsquo;t give people feedback to individuals whose application was not selected for interview. However, I thought what I could do is give some advice for people who were not successful in getting to interview, and quite honestly I would say the same to a lot of you anyway so I think it&amp;rsquo;s almost as good. I&amp;rsquo;m going to make two observations first, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll give some advice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Job Questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-08-12-job-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:25:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-08-12-job-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m recruiting at the moment. I&amp;rsquo;ve had quite a lot of people ask questions about the job and I thought rather than answer some questions for some people I would just answer all the questions on my blog and then point people here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I do I will make a couple of observations about the recruitment process. Everything is done from the application form which is stripped of identifying information. We don&amp;rsquo;t look at CVs and I don&amp;rsquo;t take into account any previous correspondence with individuals when we&amp;rsquo;re marking the application form. I totally understand why people might want to say a bit about themselves when they get in touch to ask questions but do remember that we won&amp;rsquo;t remember any of it, or your CV, or any questions that you ask. We&amp;rsquo;re not allowed to do that and quite honestly I correspond with a lot of people and so I genuinely just won&amp;rsquo;t remember individuals. With all that said here are some questions and answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-08-06-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 14:05:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-08-06-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another one in my series of &amp;ldquo;Wot I reckon&amp;rdquo; posts based on no science or evidence at all, just me trying to figure stuff out. So proceed at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is a bit more dangerous than the previous posts I wrote (for me, I mean) because it may get a little bit ranty in the middle (which I will try to avoid) but also because I don&amp;rsquo;t think it really paints me in the best light, or certainly the old me it doesn&amp;rsquo;t paint in a good light. And for all I know this perspective is unique to me and everyone else got it first time. If so, this is just a letter to my past self, but I can&amp;rsquo;t see the harm in that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decisions Decisions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-05-04-decisions-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 11:45:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-05-04-decisions-decisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part two in my &amp;ldquo;Wot I did next&amp;rdquo; series of blogs about management/ leadership in data science, and the usual caveats apply- I claim no expertise in any of the subjects therein. I&amp;rsquo;m doing and learning stuff at the moment, and throughout most of my career I&amp;rsquo;ve written them down on the internet for my own reference and in case they help others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This one is, like the last one, about something that made me more uncomfortable the further I got into it. I think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that most analysts in the NHS feel like they are not being heard, and they often feel like they don&amp;rsquo;t have autonomy over what they learn and do. I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky to have been supported by line managers who&amp;rsquo;ve given me the freedom to explore and do new things, but I know many are not. Despite the support I have received from my managers in the past (and present) I still think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that analysts are not the most influential of NHS staff and are indeed sometimes marginalised and ignored.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Job New Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-03-25-new-year-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 20:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2024-03-25-new-year-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog has existed for a long time. The first entry is nearly thirteen years old. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a big believer in blogging and I have met many people and learned many things from blogging. It kind of tailed off a bit as I got busier and I haven&amp;rsquo;t really blogged at all since I got my new job in January 2023 (just one entry since then).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used to blog technical stuff, bits of code and whatnot. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually do that any more and I unconsciously thought that my blogging days are behind me. But in the last 6 months or so I&amp;rsquo;ve got more and more interested in thinking about and describing what happens when somebody with a technical job (like my old job) gets a substantially less technical job (like my current job). Although I still talk about data science and think about data science most of the day, I never write any code any more and to be honest a decent chunk of the stuff that goes on in my team is a little beyond my grasp technically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data science panel questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2023-02-14-data-science-panel-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 15:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2023-02-14-data-science-panel-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on a panel the other day talking about data science careers (I guess there will be a link to it somewhere at some point, I’ll share it when I see it) and they’ve sent some questions out after the event because they didn’t get through them all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I may as well answer them here where everyone can see them rather than just have the people who came read them (hmm… might be a general point about working in the open there somewhere 🤔😉). There’s quite a few so I’ll take a few goes to get through them all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAP; a 10 year journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-08-23-rap-a-10-year-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 15:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-08-23-rap-a-10-year-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the earliest possible reference that I ever made to RAP in a document, part of an evaluation report I submitted nearly 10 years ago. At the time I wrote it I had hoped that it would be ceased on by the people who read it as an obviously important innovation, but I can see now that change is not so easily won. Anyway, just for fun, here it is, June 25th 2012, written in Sweave before all that newfangled RMarkdown (even that’s not newfangled now! Quarto!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data science for dummies (Goldacre)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-06-23-data-science-for-dummies-goldacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-06-23-data-science-for-dummies-goldacre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building your own tools for data science is a pretty fundamental concept, and I think it’s fair to say that it’s totally alien to most NHS bosses. I shall henceforth be showing them this excellent section from the Goldacre report. It’s not about data science as such, it’s about TREs, but it illustrates the concept beautifully&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The data science team at the music-streaming service Spotify do innovative work with data that helps drive the usability and popularity of their subscription service. For example, they extract patterns in the listening behaviour across all their users, and then use this to provide individual users with tailored recommendations for other music they might enjoy. The Spotify data science team couldn’t buy, off the shelf, a data science environment specifically built to service the needs of “a global music streaming service”. They implemented standard off-the-shelf tools for a general purpose data science environment. Then, within that raw environment, they needed to build their own tools, analytic approaches, workflows, data preparation work, and so on. A new arrival in the Spotify data science team today will find modules of code, libraries and packages – some even with nice interactive interfaces – to help them find interesting new patterns in Spotify user data. Many of these tools will feel like part of the furniture, but they were all built by their predecessors in the Spotify data science environment. Furthermore, many of these tools will not have been built to a pre-determined specification, by software developers hired to do that work to order; rather, they will emerge from a team. A single analyst might painstakingly implement a one-off analysis; if it looks like the approach will have broader use, then a more experienced developer might offer to help package it up into a function or library, with good documentation; if it becomes a commonly used approach, they might work with other analysts to create an interactive tool&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We need more than &#34;black box&#34;; systems (Goldacre)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-06-16-we-need-more-than-black-box-systems-goldacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 13:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-06-16-we-need-more-than-black-box-systems-goldacre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The system should be cautious around imagining that it can push away the challenge of TREs – and all work with NHS data – by procuring ‘black box’ services. Building platforms, capacity and modern working methods for data is a complex technical challenge, requiring deep knowledge across a range of domains: data science, data architecture, and software development; but also clinical informatics, NHS data needs, health data research, and more. This work must be done close up with real users of data, constantly iterating to improve platforms and approaches. There is no single contract that can pass over responsibility for this work. These new and complex technical challenges around data must be met by building teams, tools, methods, working practices, code and platforms&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The prevalence of code sharing (Goldacre)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-05-29-the-prevalence-of-code-sharing-goldacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 10:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-05-29-the-prevalence-of-code-sharing-goldacre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another greatest hit from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/better-broader-safer-using-health-data-for-research-and-analysis/better-broader-safer-using-health-data-for-research-and-analysis&#34;&gt;Goldacare report&lt;/a&gt;, in the section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/better-broader-safer-using-health-data-for-research-and-analysis/better-broader-safer-using-health-data-for-research-and-analysis#modern-open-working-methods-for-nhs-data-analysis&#34;&gt;open working&lt;/a&gt;, “The prevalence of code sharing” (all material reused under &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence/version/3/&#34;&gt;OGL&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“ONS covid reports: the team was unable to find any analytic code for the platform or covid analyses (but extensive and excellent open code training elsewhere)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OpenSAFELY covid reports: all code for the platform, data management and analysis all shared automatically on GitHub (declaration of interest: BG is PI on OpenSAFELY)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PHE covid reports: the team was unable to find any analytic code for PHE reports on topics such as ethnicity and COVID-19; but extensive code sharing for their (excellent) COVID-19 dashboards&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DECOVID (Turing / HDRUK PIONEER platform created for a wide range of covid research teams from a large number of universities): the team was unable to find code for the platform or analyses&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ICODA (HDRUK’s flagship COVID-19 data analysis platform initiated in June 2020): the team was unable to find code for the platform or analyses (but also no outputs to date)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;HDRUK / NHSD / BHF TRE: the team was unable to find code for the platform; but some scripts are shared for a paper describing the data accessible through it, and one research preprint (the platform’s only output to date)”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love that they did this, but that’s not why I’m writing a blog post about. What I love is the assumption that you should be able to sit at your desk with a web browser and find this stuff. That’s what “open” should mean. I’m so sick to death of being told stuff is “open source” and then I ask where it is they say “I’ll email you a copy”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Goldacre review- greatest hits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-05-22-the-goldacre-review-greatest-hits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 12:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-05-22-the-goldacre-review-greatest-hits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/better-broader-safer-using-health-data-for-research-and-analysis/better-broader-safer-using-health-data-for-research-and-analysis&#34;&gt;Goldacare review&lt;/a&gt;, I really can’t praise it enough, and I will be doing a lot of work based on it in the coming weeks and months looking at it from the perspective of my own Trust and, (with others) from the perspective of my ICS, and NHS-R. NHS-R has a couple of repos looking at matters related to the review (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nhs-r-community/statements-on-tools&#34;&gt;statement on tools&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nhs-r-community/nhs-r_vision&#34;&gt;NHS-R vision&lt;/a&gt;) and we need to do some thinking about stuff that particularly comes out of this review that we can look at (which I have started &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.github.io/notebook/docs/goldacre_review/nhs-r/&#34;&gt;doing on my own&lt;/a&gt;, community effort will follow).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In defence of the ordinary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-01-10-in-defence-of-the-ordinary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 17:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2022-01-10-in-defence-of-the-ordinary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think this might be a general cultural problem, but I notice it a lot in my field of healthcare analytics. There are lots of “case studies” and “pathfinders”, that kind of thing, groups of people who are doing amazing stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t think that it has the desired effect though. People look at these groups doing incredibly complicated things with new tools and they think it just doesn’t apply to them. Let the pathfinders pathfind and we’ll just churn out some rubbish in Excel, same as last week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In defence of looking at jobs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-12-22-in-defence-of-looking-at-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 11:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-12-22-in-defence-of-looking-at-jobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody should ever have to apologise for looking at jobs, however settled they are. Looking at jobs just means one of:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there might be a better job out there and I want to find it if there is&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I want to understand what skills people are recruiting so I can learn and do the right stuff&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I’m interested in the jobs and skills that are popular now because I want to understand the playing field of human resources in analytics as an actual or potential leader&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I want to understand my worth under agenda for change to I can advocate for the development of my professional role (and my salary &lt;img src=&#34;https://a.slack-edge.com/production-standard-emoji-assets/13.0/google-medium/1f609.png&#34; alt=&#34;:wink:&#34;&gt; ) in my current role&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any manager that doesn’t like that is a fool, a charlatan, a psychopath, or all three, and then you can add:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In defence of holiday working</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-12-16-in-defence-of-holiday-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 21:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-12-16-in-defence-of-holiday-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This might be a little bit controversial, this post. If you hate it please don’t be offended, it’s just my opinion. Totally open to being completely wrong always, especially here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a lot of people talk about the importance of taking your leave, and encouraging your staff to take your leave, and I do think it’s super important to take leave, and I certainly think if you’re managing someone you should definitely encourage them to take their leave. There is more to life than work, and having your leave can even make you better at your job when you get back, so it’s win-win, you benefit and your job benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In defence of eating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-11-24-in-defence-of-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 15:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-11-24-in-defence-of-eating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One weird thing in remote/ pandemic times is that people have started turning their cameras off when they eat. I’m all for the right to turn your camera off, I think you should be able to do that at any time without giving a reason, but I think it’s a shame if people think that they can’t eat on camera. I have therefore been glad to eat several large, difficult to eat things in meetings on camera recently, to perhaps give others the idea that it’s okay if they want to do it too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In defence of dashboards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-11-16-in-defence-of-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 22:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-11-16-in-defence-of-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had lively debates about dashboards with various people, including someone in my own team, and somebody on Twitter just mentioned that dashboards are often not used (this blog post will be my response to this tweet, not the first time I’ve answered a tweet with a blog and very on brand for me 😉).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I should acknowledge at the top that I’m The Dashboard Guy. I’ve written books about making dashboards in R. It’s my role in the data science team in which I sit. &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CDU-data-science-team/presentations/tree/main/2021-04-08%20Shiny%20in%20production&#34;&gt;production&lt;/a&gt;. It’s my thing. So take all this with as much salt as you wish, I promise I won’t be offended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make statistics sexy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-11-13-make-statistics-sexy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 23:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-11-13-make-statistics-sexy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been enjoined to make &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChrisBeeley/status/1458382972990763010?t=-jJDY6EMGq2UNuWlA1HKow&amp;amp;s=19&#34;&gt;statistics sexy&lt;/a&gt;. It’s really taking root in my brain.There are no easy answers in statistics; it’s a long, hard road. It’s rigorous, and honest, and that’s why I love it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/5HnW1YP3vTk&#34;&gt;Frank Harrell’s talk at NHS-R&lt;/a&gt; typified this. The price of truth can be very high- like binning all the data from your £1m study instead of doing what many do which is slice it into so many pieces that something looks shiny and publishing that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data saves lives- and so does open code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-09-17-data-saves-lives-and-so-does-open-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 16:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-09-17-data-saves-lives-and-so-does-open-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/data-saves-lives-reshaping-health-and-social-care-with-data-draft/data-saves-lives-reshaping-health-and-social-care-with-data-draft&#34;&gt;data saves lives&lt;/a&gt;. And look, it’s that thing that I say all the time, that I have pinned on my Twitter profile, the thing I’ve heard time and time again for a decade that everybody just stands around nodding at and nothing actually changes. I quote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;working-in-the-open&#34;&gt;“Working in the open&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Public services are built with public money, and so the code &lt;a href=&#34;https://service-manual.nhs.uk/service-standard/12-make-new-source-code-open&#34;&gt;they are based on should be made available&lt;/a&gt; for digital pioneers across the health and care system, and those working with it, to reuse and build on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pay and reward</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-08-19-pay-and-reward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 22:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-08-19-pay-and-reward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading No Rules Rules, the Netflix management book. It’s really good, lots of interesting stuff in there about doing things differently and although clearly there’s a lot I can’t do in the NHS, there are lessons in there for sure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve just read the bit about paying people top of market rate and I’m so happy because it describes loads of people who are on $250,000, crazy money, moping around and leaving because they can get a 40% pay rise somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphs &gt; tables</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-07-19-graphs-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 17:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-07-19-graphs-tables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One phenomenon that I find very strange in the NHS (and elsewhere, probably, I’ve never worked anywhere else) is the obsession people have with having tables of numbers instead of graphs. I have encountered this absolutely everywhere. People really want to know whether something is 21.4% of the whole or 19.2% of the whole and they can’t tell by looking at the beautiful graph that you’ve drawn.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I saw an analysis today which had nine separate tables of proportions. I’m going to go out on a limb and say no human being can understand a thing of such complexity. Nine tables, each with three categories, 27 proportions given. You could fit the whole thing on one graph and it would be readily apparent how they compare with each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop punishing people with data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-07-18-stop-punishing-people-with-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-07-18-stop-punishing-people-with-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any observed statistical regularity will tend to collapse once pressure is placed upon it for control purposes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was then popularised by Strathern as&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a measure becomes a target, it ceases to be a good measure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, so ordinary. What else do we all know? League tables are a bad idea too. Somewhat related to Goodhart’s law, the problem with league tables is that they often ignore nuance. &amp;ldquo;Bad&amp;rdquo; schools aren’t bad, they just have an intake that starts way behind. &amp;ldquo;Bad&amp;rdquo; surgeons aren’t bad, they just take on the more complex cases or work in a geographical location where there are more complex cases. There are ways of trying to balance out this bias, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tes.com/news/revealed-top-ranked-schools-fairer-league-tables&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;value added&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; in the case of schools (being married to a teacher, I hear a lot about this one), and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23426886/&#34;&gt;case mix adjustment in the case of surgeons&lt;/a&gt;. Although these methods go some way to ironing out problems there is always the chance that an unmeasured variable is affecting the results and distorting the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shoddy data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-07-14-shoddy-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-07-14-shoddy-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know, naming no names because I’ll get in trouble but someone somewhere has paid for some data from a proprietary vendor and they’re shipping absolutely unusable garbage data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They won’t fix it because “no-one else has complained”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HAVE SOME PRIDE IN WHAT YOU’RE DOING. How about that? How about fixing it because it’s an embarrassment? I’m a random idiot in some random NHS Trust in the countryside and I couldn’t sleep if my database looked like what you’re sending.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing data science teams in the trenches</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-06-01-managing-data-science-teams-in-the-trenches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-06-01-managing-data-science-teams-in-the-trenches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re systematically devaluing management and leadership in the analyst space, and I encounter a lot of people who think that a day with no code written is a day wasted. I do write code, but I do a lot of other valuable stuff too. I’ve written this post as someone who is very new to managing people with my personal opinion, so just like my posts on proxied SSL with Apache, there is your caveat emptor 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do we want from senior analysts in the NHS?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-05-31-what-do-we-want-from-senior-analysts-in-the-nhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 12:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-05-31-what-do-we-want-from-senior-analysts-in-the-nhs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to write this for ages and I’ve just had a rather silly conversation on Twitter about managers and leaders in the NHS which has inspired me to get on with it. I think most people are agreed that we have A Problem with mangers and leaders in the analytic space. Much ink has been spilled in the subject, and I think that the two main conclusions of all this ink are broadly accepted by everyone. They are, briefly:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL versus analytic tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-03-26-sql-versus-analytic-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 10:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-03-26-sql-versus-analytic-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_johnmackintosh/status/1374986918878965760?s=19&#34;&gt;tweet from my NHS-R buddy John MacKintosh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Two schools of thought :&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1. Do as much as possible using SQL (joins/ munging/ calculations and analysis) so that your analysis is portable between different BI / Viz tools&lt;br&gt;&#xA;2. Do the basics (e.g. joins and simple aggregates) in SQL, calcs and analysis in front end tools”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a great question, and I don’t mean to detract from its greatness when I say it is over simplistic. It’s an important question, and I have a lot to say on the subject, so much so in fact that I’m going to answer a tweet with a blog, which is very on brand for me 😄.When we think of data scientists and data engineers, we tend to think of data engineers providing beautifully normal and rapid data structures and data scientists wrangling them with a mix of SQL and R/ Python/ whatever. But in my experience it doesn’t really work cleanly that way, and nor should it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building generic Shiny applications with a data module</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-02-18-building-generic-shiny-applications-with-a-data-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 16:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-02-18-building-generic-shiny-applications-with-a-data-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re rebuilding our patient experience dashboard at the moment, partly to incorporate some of the work that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CDU-data-science-team/positive_about_change_text_mining&#34;&gt;we’re doing on text mining&lt;/a&gt; and partly to connect it up to other types of information we have like staff experience and clinical outcomes. It has to be reusable because we’re using it as the basis of the text mining dashboard that we’re building for any provider trust to use with their friends and family test data. We’re trying to make everything reusable anyway partly because the different bits of the NHS should all cooperate and produce stuff together that everyone can use and partly because we’re realising that when you make code reusable the first person who can reuse it is you, 6 months later on a similar project.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So we have a patient experience dashboard that we want to hook up to our other data in our own context, and we have other trusts who want to take what we produce and hook their stuff in to it. An obvious approach is to use modules in Shiny and have a data module at the heart of the operation, which can take account of the different datasets available in each context. The next level would be a “summary type” module which would bring together all of the inputs and outputs for a particular type of data- one for patient experience, one for staff experience, etc. And the bottom level would be submodules which would carry out the individual tasks- one module to produce graphical summaries, one to produce downloadable reports, etc. We would use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/golem/index.html&#34;&gt;{golem} package&lt;/a&gt; for all the reasons that we normally use {golem} (help with dependencies, packaging, testing, and deployment)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The basic structure would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing plot characteristics in Shiny modules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-01-29-accessing-plot-characteristics-in-shiny-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 22:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2021-01-29-accessing-plot-characteristics-in-shiny-modules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was my New Year’s resolution to blog more and that’s going really well because this is the first blog I’ve done all year and it’s nearly the end of January. Well, I suppose to be fair I did do &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdu-data-science-team.github.io/team-blog/posts/2021-01-20-a-new-github-release-and-future-projects/&#34;&gt;a post on our team blog&lt;/a&gt; but that feels like I’m making excuses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, never mind! This is a quick blog post because this problem I had the other day has, as far as I can tell, absolutely no Google juice at all and it stumped me for ages, even though it is very simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serving RStudio Connect content to logged in and anonymous users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-10-19-serving-rstudio-connect-content-to-logged-in-and-anonymous-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 17:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-10-19-serving-rstudio-connect-content-to-logged-in-and-anonymous-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have our &lt;a href=&#34;https://involve.nottshc.nhs.uk:8443/experience/&#34;&gt;patient feedback dashboard&lt;/a&gt; in the open where anyone can see what Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust’s patients are saying about us. Now I’ve got a Connect licence I thought perhaps I might build another version for our staff where I put stuff that we can’t share- for example the comments of people who click the “I do not wish to share this comment” box.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I don’t want to build and maintain two versions, that would be hideous, and I was going to put a litte&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyst, analyse thyself</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-10-02-analyst-analyse-thyself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 09:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-10-02-analyst-analyse-thyself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work in a small (growing) team of data scientists and we’re part of a larger analytic unit which has a focus on innovation in analytics (hence us) and public health methods. We have a pretty broad remit to do interesting and useful stuff and we focus on things that we think are useful (for example, applying data science methods to problems relating to equity of access to services) and things that people ask us to help with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiny modules for beginners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-08-05-shiny-modules-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 17:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-08-05-shiny-modules-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen some discussion on the Internet about whether people learning Shiny should start with modules or if they’re an advanced topic. I’m not going to link to any examples because this post is definitely not me saying- hey look at this rubbish over here, here’s why it’s wrong. I’ve seen a couple of posts talking about it. But I just thought I would chip in my perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really love modules and they solve a lot of problems, and I think they could be a great thing for a beginner to learn. No reason at all why beginners can’t learn them. The only caution I would give those learners is that some things can be weird or fiddly with modules. So if you’re learning at your own pace, and want to do everything really neatly and use industry standards, great, go for it. But if you want to throw up a Shiny application to impress your boss (for example) and learn by doing then you may find yourself going down some very long, dark rabbit holes trying to get the particular thing you want working. (and yes, I am writing this post now because I have been down a few myself recently 😀)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started in data science for healthcare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-07-13-getting-started-in-data-science-for-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 15:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-07-13-getting-started-in-data-science-for-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just recruited to a data science post at Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust and I’ve been asked for feedback by several people about how to get started in data science in healthcare, and indeed how to get a job in data science in healthcare. I will also be recruiting another data scientist for our team in a few months. This post is designed to give you a feel for what we were looking for in the job that I just recruited to, as well as to the job that is coming up. They’re slightly different skill sets as I will discuss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Connect behind the firewall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-06-10-rstudio-connect-behind-the-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 16:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-06-10-rstudio-connect-behind-the-firewall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part II of what would otherwise have been a far-too-long post about configuring RStudio Connect. A bit of back story, particularly for those of you who might have hit this from a Google search (which does happen, JetPack tells me) and don’t know who the heck I am and what I do all day. Here’s what I said in part I:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using RStudio stuff on the server for a long time. I started using Shiny community edition back in 2013 for an application that is totally open and so doesn’t need authenticating. Then two years ago I started deploying Shiny applications that people authenticated to behind our Trust firewall using Shiny Pro. I have wanted to use RStudio Connect for a long time but it was hard to get the funding together for it given how things are with austerity since the banking crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Connect in the cloud</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-06-10-rstudio-connect-in-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 16:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-06-10-rstudio-connect-in-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using RStudio stuff on the server for a long time. I started using Shiny community edition back in 2013 for an application that is totally open and so doesn’t need authenticating. Then two years ago I started deploying Shiny applications that people authenticated to behind our Trust firewall using Shiny Pro. I have wanted to use RStudio Connect for a long time but it was hard to get the funding together for it given how things are with austerity since the banking crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productionising R at Nottinghamshire Healthcare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-05-26-productionising-r-at-nottinghamshire-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 17:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-05-26-productionising-r-at-nottinghamshire-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m hopeful we’re moving into a bit of a new phase with using R in my Trust so I thought I’d outline the direction of travel, to see if it chimes with anyone else and just to keep people up to date about what we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve used Shiny for some years now, maybe 7, and we have applications behind the firewall and in the cloud which are well used by the staff who need them. We’ve also been building our skills (R and data ops, which is a whole other post) and I’m hopeful that we’re ready for the next phase, which I would call the “productionise” phase. There are two main tasks to achieve before we’ve really got the work that we’re doing nicely embedded in everyday practice at Nottinghamshire Healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>app.R and global.R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-04-03-app-r-and-global-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 18:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-04-03-app-r-and-global-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m doing some Shiny training this year and I want to teach whatever the new thinking is so I’ve been reading Hadley Wickham’s online book &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastering-shiny.org/&#34;&gt;Mastering Shiny&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a couple of things that I’ve noticed where Shiny is moving on, so if you want to keep up to date I suggest you have a look. I’m going to pick out a few here. Firstly, note that in Shiny 1.5 (which is not released at the time of writing) all code in the R/ directory will be sourced automatically. This is a very good idea, I’ve got loads of source(“useful_code.R”, local = TRUE) lines in some of my applications, so it gets rid of all that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data science for human beings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-03-27-data-science-for-human-beings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 10:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-03-27-data-science-for-human-beings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone just emailed me to ask me about getting into data science. They knew all the usual stuff, linear algebra, Python, all that stuff, so I thought I’d talk about the other side of data science. It’s all stuff I say whenever I talk about data science, but I’ve never written it down so I thought I may as well blog it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three things that are probably harder to learn that will make you stand out at interview and be a better data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NHS data science and software licensing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-03-23-nhs-data-science-and-software-licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 13:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-03-23-nhs-data-science-and-software-licensing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m writing something about software licensing and IP in NHS data science projects at the moment. I don’t think I ever dreamed about doing this, but I’ve noticed that a lot of people working in data science and related fields are confused about some of the issues and I would like to produce a set of facts (and opinions) which are based on a thorough reading of the subject and share them with interested parties. It’s a big job but I thought I’d trail a bit of it here and there as I go. Here’s the summary at the end of the licences section.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Survey Munge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-03-04-the-great-survey-munge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-03-04-the-great-survey-munge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned on Twitter the other day, I have this rather ugly spreadsheet that comes from some online survey software that requires quite a lot of cleaning in order to upload it to the database. I had an old version written in base R but the survey has changed so I’ve updated it to tidyverse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And this is where tidyverse absolutely shines. Using it for this job really made me realise how much help it gives you when you’ve got a big mess and you want to rapidly turn it into a proper dataset, renaming, recoding, and generally cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly find the mean of survey questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-02-25-rapidly-find-the-mean-of-survey-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-02-25-rapidly-find-the-mean-of-survey-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the last blog post, I’ve got quite a nice way of generating lots of means from a survey dataset. This one relies on the fact that I’m averaging questions that go 2.1, 2.2, 2.3, and 3.1, 3.2, 3.3, so I can look for all questions that start with “2.”, “3.”, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(tidyverse)&#xA;&#xA;survey &amp;lt;- survey %&amp;gt;% bind_cols(&#xA;  &#xA;  map(paste0(as.character(2 : 9), &amp;#34;.&amp;#34;), function(x) {&#xA;    &#xA;    return_value &amp;lt;- survey %&amp;gt;% &#xA;      select(starts_with(x)) %&amp;gt;% &#xA;      rowMeans(., na.rm = TRUE) %&amp;gt;% &#xA;      as.data.frame()&#xA;    &#xA;    names(return_value) &amp;lt;- paste0(&amp;#34;Question &amp;#34;, x)&#xA;    &#xA;    return(return_value)&#xA;  }) &#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This returns the original dataset plus the averages of each question, labelled “Question 2”, “Question 3”, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting words on a survey dataset to numbers for analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-02-18-converting-words-on-a-survey-dataset-to-numbers-for-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 13:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-02-18-converting-words-on-a-survey-dataset-to-numbers-for-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As always, I have very little time for blogging (sorry) but I just came up with a neat way of converting “Strongly Agree”, “Always”, all that stuff that you get on survey based datasets into numbers ready for analysis. It’s automatic, so it will play havoc with any word based questions- analyse them in a separate script.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here it is&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(tidyverse)&#xA;&#xA;survey &amp;lt;- map_df(survey, function(x) {&#xA;  &#xA;  if(sum(grepl(&amp;#34;Agree&amp;#34;, unlist(x), ignore.case = TRUE)) &amp;gt; 0) {&#xA;    &#xA;    return(case_when(&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Strongly agree&amp;#34; ~ 10,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Agree&amp;#34; ~ 7.5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Neither agree nor disagree&amp;#34; ~ 5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Disagree&amp;#34; ~ 2.5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Strongly disagree&amp;#34; ~ 0,&#xA;      TRUE ~ NA_real_&#xA;    ))&#xA;  } else if(sum(grepl(&amp;#34;Always&amp;#34;, unlist(x), ignore.case = TRUE)) &amp;gt; 0){&#xA;    &#xA;    return(case_when(&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Always&amp;#34; ~ 10,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Often&amp;#34; ~ 7.5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Sometimes&amp;#34; ~ 5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Rarely&amp;#34; ~ 2.5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Never&amp;#34; ~ 0,&#xA;      TRUE ~ NA_real_&#xA;    ))&#xA;  &#xA;  } else if(sum(grepl(&amp;#34;Dissatisfied&amp;#34;, unlist(x), ignore.case = TRUE)) &amp;gt; 0){&#xA;    &#xA;    return(case_when(&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Very satisfied&amp;#34; ~ 10,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Satisfied&amp;#34; ~ 7.5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Neither satisfied nor dissatisfied&amp;#34; ~ 5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Dissatisfied&amp;#34; ~ 2.5,&#xA;      x == &amp;#34;Very dissatisfied&amp;#34; ~ 0,&#xA;      TRUE ~ NA_real_&#xA;    ))&#xA;&#xA;  } else {&#xA;    &#xA;    return(x)&#xA;  }&#xA;})&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Glorious. R makes it too easy, really, I think, sometimes 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decade round up post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-01-19-decade-round-up-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 09:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2020-01-19-decade-round-up-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve got into the habit of writing a yearly roundup blog post (see this blog, passim), based on a suggested framework by David Allen. Since this is the end of a decade I thought it would be fun to do one for the whole decade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical&#34;&gt;Physical&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regular readers will know that as far as physical goes I have spent most of the decade getting progressively sicker with two different diseases, beating both, and then having complications from the liver transplant that saved me from the first one. Perhaps the pinnacle was having a colectomy/ splenectomy in September 2017, bleeding a lot and being very sick for several weeks afterwards and then running a marathon in 3 hours 44 minutes just 18 months later in February 2019. I went on to win silver in the 5K in the British Transplant Games in July of this year, but am now not currently running due to complications from my liver transplant. I’ll be fine, I need to go and see the doctors next year, they’ll sort me out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My superpower (a talk I gave about being ill)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-12-16-my-superpower-a-talk-i-gave-about-being-ill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-12-16-my-superpower-a-talk-i-gave-about-being-ill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this post is nothing to do with R, or Linux, or statistics, or any of the usual stuff. It’s about me. It’s more than possible that you’re not very interested in that so consider yourself warned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long time readers will know I’ve had some pretty serious health problems over the years. I haven’t really talked about it much on here. To be honest I was frightened that people might be put off working with me if they thought I would be off sick a lot and I was also frightened at one point that I might actually be permanently unable to work if the liver disease wasn’t treatable. So I avoided talking about it with the wider world, although the people I directly work with know all about it (it’s hard to miss, really, when someone comes to work with end stage liver disease).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NHS-R conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-12-08-nhs-r-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 12:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-12-08-nhs-r-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I recently just got back from the NHS-R community conference, which was amazing of course, and it’s got me in the mood to share, so I’m writing a few blog posts. I’ve got some more in depth stuff to say about where I think NHS-R is/ should be going, but this is the “feels” one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned on Twitter, I love the NHS and I love R so I’m obviously going to enjoy the NHS-R conference. It was really good and the standard of talks and workshops was really high. Much bigger and better than last year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authenticating using LDAP from Active Directory using Shiny Server Pro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-11-06-authenticating-using-ldap-from-active-directory-using-shiny-server-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 18:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-11-06-authenticating-using-ldap-from-active-directory-using-shiny-server-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right, I promised I would write this a very long time ago and I still haven’t done it. I’ve just got back from the NHS-R community conference (see an upcoming post) and I’m in a sharing mood, and besides someone just asked me about this on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So setting up LDAP based authentication on Shiny Server Pro via Windows Active Directory. Do note that this post is about using Active Directory. If you’re not doing that a lot of this stuff will not apply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add label to shinydashboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-10-31-add-label-to-shinydashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 11:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-10-31-add-label-to-shinydashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’m sticking my neck out a bit here, and there’s a simple way to doing this that I haven’t found, but I’ve looked pretty hard and “add label to sidebar shiny dashboard” has basically no Google juice at all, and I should know because I’ve been staring at it for half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you want to add a simple, static label to a shinydashboard sidebar. If you just add it with p() it isn’t aligned nicely with the rest of the sidebar controls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The analysts&#39; manifesto</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-08-08-the-analysts-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 14:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-08-08-the-analysts-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was at an event a little while ago and there was talk of change coming for healthcare analysts. With the advent of population health management we were going to finally get the recognition we as a profession deserve and would get the training and tools necessary to deliver the improvements we all know that data can give.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I put my hand up and said, in essence, we’ve heard it all before and I’ll believe it when I see it. I’m tired, frankly, of reading policy documents that lay out all these amazing new ways of working that just never happen because we’re not given the time and space by senior management and have to spend our time running around sending all this pointless data to all these different bodies that a lot of the time seem to just throw the data on the pile and then forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python, working together, and productionising code at Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-07-02-python-working-together-and-productionising-code-at-nottinghamshire-healthcare-nhs-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 16:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-07-02-python-working-together-and-productionising-code-at-nottinghamshire-healthcare-nhs-trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone just asked me a question on Twitter and I was most of the way through what would have been several tweets before I thought perhaps it would work better as a blog post. I’m going to answer the question first, and then talk some more about the context and what I’m hoping to achieve where I am and (with the advent of more collaborative working through the ICS) in the wider system. So I’ve been using scikit-learn to train a classifier to predict non attendance at healthcare appointments and the question to me was “What made you choose Python rather than R for this one? Which classifier are you using?”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A note for Kindle readers of my Shiny book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-05-25-a-note-for-kindle-readers-of-my-shiny-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-05-25-a-note-for-kindle-readers-of-my-shiny-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone has been in touch with me to say that the Kindle version has no chapter numbers and they were finding it difficult to figure out which bit of the book went with which bit in the repository.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a little video just to run through all the chapters and which code file goes with which bit of the book. While I was doing it I noticed the minimal example from chapter 2 is missing. It’s only small so I don’t think anybody will be too bothered about typing it but I’ve put it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ChrisBeeley/8924a0bfc1fc7853e7a7b859a2a133f0&#34;&gt;a Gist&lt;/a&gt; anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of patient experience data at Nottinghamshire Healthcare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-04-05-the-future-of-patient-experience-data-at-nottinghamshire-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 10:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-04-05-the-future-of-patient-experience-data-at-nottinghamshire-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked about my plans for patient experience data in quite a few different forums recently, but it just occurred to me that it isn’t written down anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who’s spent any time with me in meetings will know I’m a stickler for writing things down, so here it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I launched a Shiny application to explore our patient experience data about 6 years ago. It was pretty early days for Shiny and it seemed pretty whizzy and exciting at the time. Over time I added more features but it seemed less and less whizzy and exciting, and to be honest I was too busy nearly dying twice to worry about it (see this blog, passim, don’t worry I’m absolutely fine now)·&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding line returns in RMarkdown in a loop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-31-adding-line-returns-in-rmarkdown-in-a-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 16:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-31-adding-line-returns-in-rmarkdown-in-a-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another one that’s for me when I forget. The internet seems strangely reluctant to tell me how to do this, yet &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/49561077/creating-a-new-line-within-an-rmarkdown-chunk&#34;&gt;here it is&lt;/a&gt; buried in the answer to something else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you are writing an RMarkdown document and wish to produce text with line returns between each piece. I can never work out how to do it. It’s very simple. Just two spaces and then \n. Like this ” \n”. Here’s some real code with it in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Producing RMarkdown reports with Plumber</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-19-producing-rmarkdown-reports-with-plumber/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 18:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-19-producing-rmarkdown-reports-with-plumber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t going to post this until I got it working on the server but I’ve got the wrong train ticket and am stuck in London St Pancras until 7pm so I thought I’d be productive and put it up now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I launched a new version of the patient experience dashboard. I forget if I mentioned it on here or not. I think not. It’s here &lt;a href=&#34;http://109.74.194.173:8080/apps/SUCE/&#34;&gt;http://109.74.194.173:8080/apps/SUCE/&lt;/a&gt; and the code is here &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisBeeley/patient-experience-dashboard&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ChrisBeeley/patient-experience-dashboard&lt;/a&gt;. (I should add that I’ve launched a bit early because of an event so it will be a little buggy- forgive me for that).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppress console output with ggplot, purrr, and RMarkdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-17-suppress-console-output-with-ggplot-purrr-and-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 18:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-17-suppress-console-output-with-ggplot-purrr-and-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.net/?p=1143&#34;&gt;I posted a while back&lt;/a&gt; about producing several plots at once with RMarkdown and purrr and how to suppress the console output in the document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, I just spotted someone on Twitter having a similar problem and it turns out that the solution actually doesn’t work in ggplot! Interesting…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For ggplot, you need to excellent function walk() which is like map() except it’s called for its side effects (like disk access) rather than for its output per se.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A world of #plotthedots and what else?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-03-a-world-of-plotthedots-and-what-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 09:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-03-03-a-world-of-plotthedots-and-what-else/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reproduced above is a recent exchange on Twitter. I’d better open by saying this blog post is not impugning the work of Samantha Riley or any other plot the dots people. On the contrary, the whole #plotthedots movement is an important part of a cultural change that is happening within the NHS at the moment. But I would like to take up the rhetorical device Samantha uses, to explore the issues that we have understanding data in the NHS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citing R packages in RMarkdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-02-17-citing-r-packages-in-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 15:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-02-17-citing-r-packages-in-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t really done much in the way of citing papers in the last couple of years, I’ve spent my time either messing around with Shiny servers or databases or writing RMarkdown reports- and being horribly ill, of course, haha!- see this blog, passim. Don’t worry, I’m as fit as a flea now 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’ve been citing one or two papers today and I’ve found it very easy to cite both papers and R packages in RMarkdown, so I’m here to tell you not to ignore it because it’s too hard, just do it. Step one: add the bottom line of the following to your YAML header:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dplyr function to replace nested ifelse (like SQL CASE WHEN)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-02-03-dplyr-function-to-replace-nested-ifelse-like-sql-case-when/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 17:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-02-03-dplyr-function-to-replace-nested-ifelse-like-sql-case-when/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate nested ifelse statements in R code. I absolutely hate them. They are just ugly and difficult to read. I found this lovely function in dplyr called case_when (which is like the SQL CASE WHEN if you know that) that banished them forever. It’s easier if I just show you (this is from the documentation)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;x &amp;lt;- 1:50&#xA;case_when(&#xA;  x %% 35 == 0 ~ &amp;#34;fizz buzz&amp;#34;,&#xA;  x %% 5 == 0 ~ &amp;#34;fizz&amp;#34;,&#xA;  x %% 7 == 0 ~ &amp;#34;buzz&amp;#34;,&#xA;  TRUE ~ as.character(x)&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;How wonderful is that? No more nested ifelse!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data science accelerator lesson one- build a pipeline and ship the code!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-01-20-data-science-accelerator-lesson-one-build-a-pipeline-and-ship-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 17:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-01-20-data-science-accelerator-lesson-one-build-a-pipeline-and-ship-the-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My exciting news is that I was accepted onto the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/data-science-accelerator-programme/introduction-to-the-data-science-accelerator&#34;&gt;data science accelerator&lt;/a&gt; and have been doing it since late December. My project, basically, is all about using natural language processing to better understand the patient experience data that we collect (and, if I have time, the staff experience data too). Here are the goals:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using an unsupervised technique, generate a novel way of categorising the text data to give us a different perspective. We already have tagged data but I would like to interrogate the usefulness of the tags that we have used&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generate a system that, given a comment or set of comments, can find other comments within the data that are semantically similar. Note that this system will need to run live on the server, since it would be impossible to store the semantic similarity of every comment to every other comment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generate a system that, instead of searching by word, searches by similarity to that word&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Produce a supervised learning algorithm which can be trained on a sample of tagged comments and then produce tags for comments that it has not previously seen&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Produce a sentiment analysis function that can tag every comment in a database with how positive or negative it is&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Produce reporting functions that can compute overall sentiment for a group of documents (e.g. of a particular service area) and optionally describe the change in sentiment over time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure if I’m going to get through all of it but I’ve made a decent start. I’ve made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/b/GlmtpsqB/data-science-accelerator&#34;&gt;Trello board&lt;/a&gt; and there’s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisBeeley/naturallanguageprocessing&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Year&amp;#8217;s post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-01-08-new-years-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 21:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2019-01-08-new-years-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this is my annual New Year’s post, it’s an idea from David Allen that I’ve done &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisbeeley.net/?p=1052&#34;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2018 was the year that I was finally (pretty much) better. I had my bowel and spleen removed in August 2017 and bled in quite a scary way, but by the time 2018 rolled around I was running 9 miles, building mileage ready for a marathon in May. It’s been a great year. I did have some pretty scary health problems (that I won’t go into) but it all worked out in the finish and I’m pretty much back to working and being happy with my family just as I was all the way back in 2014 before everything started to go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tidy text talk and some stuff from my Shiny book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-11-16-a-tidy-text-talk-and-some-stuff-from-my-shiny-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 14:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-11-16-a-tidy-text-talk-and-some-stuff-from-my-shiny-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick post to show some of the stuff that I’ve published/ presented/ put on GitHub recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So my Shiny book, Web Application Development with R using Shiny, 3rd edition, is out, and I’ve forked the code from the publisher’s repository onto my own GitHub to make it easier to find.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And I’ve got another book about Shiny out which is all about UI development with Shiny, and I’ve forked the code from that onto my GitHub, too&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing stacked barcharts the tidyverse way</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=1170/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 17:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=1170/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don’t judge me, but I do spend quite a lot of time making stacked barcharts of survey data. I’m trying to go full tidyverse (see this blog, passim) and there is a very neat way of doing it in the tidyverse which is very easy to expand out into functions, or purrr, or whatever. Of course, me being me I can never remember what it is so I end up reading the same SO answers over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Produce tables in loop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-10-16-produce-tables-in-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 16:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-10-16-produce-tables-in-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another one for me before I forget, I seem to have terrible problems writing headings and tables in a loop in RMarkdown. Everything gets crushed together because the line returns don’t seem to work properly and either the table or the headings get mangled. Well here it is, the thing I just did that worked:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;for(i in 1:2){&#xA;&#xA;  cat(&amp;#34;Heading &amp;#34;, i, &amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;)&#xA;  &#xA;  cat(&amp;#34;===========================&amp;#34;)&#xA;  &#xA;  pandoc.table(iris)&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s it! Don’t put any other weird “\n”s or [HTML line breaks which I now realise WordPress will interpret literally] in. You don’t need them!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The shinyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-10-02-the-shinyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 13:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-10-02-the-shinyverse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty sure I’ve made up the word shinyverse, to refer to all the packages that either use or complement Shiny. This is a non-exhaustive list of shinyverse packages, mainly for my benefit when I inevitably forget, but if it’s useful for you too then that’s good too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/shiny.semantic/index.html&#34;&gt;shiny.semantic&lt;/a&gt; adds support for the Semantic UI library to Shiny. Useful if you want your Shiny apps to look a bit different or there’s something in the library that you need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filling in non missing elements by row (Survey Monkey masterclass)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-10-02-filling-in-non-missing-elements-by-row-survey-monkey-masterclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-10-02-filling-in-non-missing-elements-by-row-survey-monkey-masterclass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There must be other people out there doing this, so I’ll share this neat thing I found today. Quite often, you’ll have a dataset that has a lot of columns, only one of which will have something in it for each row. Survey Monkey, in particular, produces these kinds of sheets if you use branching logic. So if you work in one bit of the Trust, your team name will be found in one column, but if you branched elsewhere in the survey because you work somewhere else, it is in another column. Lots of columns, but each individual has only one non-missing element in each (because they only work in one place and only see that question once).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In praise of awkward questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-09-18-in-praise-of-awkward-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 20:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-09-18-in-praise-of-awkward-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to a conference last week, more of a meet up really, and they presented the results of the work that we’ve all been doing, indicating that there were several statistically significant improvements in the expected direction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m sure the analysis is well intentioned and basically correct, so I didn’t really have any problem with it, but my arm shot up anyway, because I wanted to see more details of the analysis. The results were so good, I was just curious to see how they were so good really- what were the 95% confidence intervals, the sample sizes, alpha levels, just the nitty gritty of the analysis so I could really get all the detail of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter, Python, interactive web frameworks, and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-09-03-jupyter-python-interactive-web-frameworks-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 08:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-09-03-jupyter-python-interactive-web-frameworks-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago on Twitter I said the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Increasingly, RStudio’s products are so good that I feel a lot of my advice to my organisation is “buy a lot of RStudio products”. I love RStudio (I have a tattoo of their logo on my arm, even!) and they clearly give a lot of stuff away (we used their products for nothing for *years*). But I wish I could at least acknowledge some competition in this arena. As far as I can see, if you want to develop a cutting edge data science team with R, it’s RStudio all the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Producing several plots at once with RMarkdown and purrr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-08-17-producing-several-plots-at-once-with-rmarkdown-and-purrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-08-17-producing-several-plots-at-once-with-rmarkdown-and-purrr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple example of using purrr and RMarkdown to produce several plots all at once.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;invisible( # suppress console output from hist()&#xA;  map(c(5, 6, 7), function(x) { # values to feed to filter function&#xA;    &#xA;    iris %&amp;gt;%&#xA;      filter(Sepal.Length &amp;lt; x) %&amp;gt;% # just Sepal.Length &amp;lt; 5, 6, and 7&#xA;      pull(Petal.Width) %&amp;gt;% # extract Petal.Width vector&#xA;      hist(breaks = 20, main = paste0(&amp;#34;Histogram of &amp;lt; &amp;#34;, x)) # graph&#xA;  })&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Pro in a Windows/ NHS environment, part 1: The curse of Kerberos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-07-12-shiny-pro-in-a-windows-nhs-environment-part-1-the-curse-of-kerberos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 14:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-07-12-shiny-pro-in-a-windows-nhs-environment-part-1-the-curse-of-kerberos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right, here goes. Let’s tell the story. I’ve been working on this for months, not because it’s particularly hard, but because I really didn’t know what I was doing. We are a health trust in the UK (NHS), and we’ve been using Shiny on a privately hosted Linode server (Ubuntu) in the cloud for a long time. You can see it &lt;a href=&#34;http://109.74.194.173:8080/apps/SUCE/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve done this (hosted it in the wild) because none of the data is private. It’s patient experience data. We want it to be public. If anything, we want people to steal it. To be honest it’s looking a bit tatty. I was proud of it in 2012, now not so much. I’m working on a new version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passing strings as variables from a Shiny app into dplyr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-06-13-passing-strings-as-variables-from-a-shiny-app-into-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 12:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-06-13-passing-strings-as-variables-from-a-shiny-app-into-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been sort of waiting until I understood this thoroughly, and I was going to write a very detailed blog post about it, and although I do understand it a lot better now than I did, I’m still not at the point where I would write an authoritative blog post about it confidently because there are too many things that I don’t understand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I’m aware that there are people out there right now who are trying to write dplyr code that takes strings as variable inputs, passed in from a Shiny interface, and I know how difficult it is to Google, because I Googled it myself. So I’m going to at least show you what to do, and talk a bit about it, and then maybe I’ll come back to it when I’ve understood it better myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectively hide text with JavaScript in RMarkdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-05-29-selectively-hide-text-with-javascript-in-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 09:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-05-29-selectively-hide-text-with-javascript-in-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess this is one of those where I kind of did know it was possible, really. If I’d thought it through. But I’ve always not been sure how easy it would be and I’ve been in too much of a rush.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I’m trying to move my organisation onto HTML instead of Word. HTML is easier to output and parse, and it’s interactive with a bit of JavaScript. I used the DT package in R to put some tables into an RMarkdown document and of course that’s very nice because they’re pageable, orderable, and searchable out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recoding to NA with dplyr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-05-15-recoding-to-na-with-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 10:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-05-15-recoding-to-na-with-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just very quickly again, still horribly busy, but this has been annoying me for ages and I finally figured it out. When you’re using recode from dplyr, you can’t recode to NA if you’re recoding to other things that aren’t NA, because it complains that the types aren’t compatible. So don’t do this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;  mutate(Relationship = recode(Relationship, &amp;#34;Co-Habiting&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;Co&amp;#34;, &#xA;    &amp;#34;Divorced&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;Di&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Married&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;Ma&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Civil partnership&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;CI&amp;#34;&#xA;    &amp;#34;Single&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;Si&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Widowed&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;Wi&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Separated&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;Se&amp;#34;, &#xA;    &amp;#34;Prefer not to say&amp;#34; = NA))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use na_if() instead:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checking memory usage in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-05-01-checking-memory-usage-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 09:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-05-01-checking-memory-usage-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, I cannot believe I didn’t blog this. I just tried to find it on my own blog and I must have forgotten. Anyway, it’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/48953571/486245&#34;&gt;an answer I gave on Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; a little while ago, to do with measuring how much memory your R objects are using.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;install.packages(&amp;#34;pryr&amp;#34;)&#xA;&#xA;library(pryr)&#xA;&#xA;object_size(1:10)&#xA;## 88 B&#xA;&#xA;object_size(mean)&#xA;## 832 B&#xA;&#xA;object_size(mtcars)&#xA;## 6.74 kB&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is from Hadley Wickham’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://adv-r.had.co.nz/memory.html&#34;&gt;advanced R&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convert icons to different colours</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-04-17-convert-icons-to-different-colours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 12:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-04-17-convert-icons-to-different-colours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m horribly, horribly busy (stay tuned until mid May-ish to hear about what I’ve been up to) but I’ve just done something so quickly and easily that I couldn’t resist sharing it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I’ve downloaded a little man icon, I’m going to use it in a pictogram to show the percentage of people who agree with something. Just a bit of fun for a presentation. The man is black, but I thought it would be nice to have green men who are saying happy things (“I felt supported”, that kind of thing) and red men who are saying unhappy things (“I felt isolated”, e.g.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Shiny Server over SSL with Apache on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-03-22-securing-shiny-server-over-ssl-with-apache-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 09:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-03-22-securing-shiny-server-over-ssl-with-apache-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I couldn’t find a guide for precisely this on the Internet, securing your Shiny Server over SSL (with Apache), but I did find the following links which were very useful and which I only adapted slightly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do have a read of the following if you’re so inclined, they’re both very useful, but neither told me exactly what to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ipub.com/shiny-https/&#34;&gt;https://ipub.com/shiny-https/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.rstudio.com/hc/en-us/articles/213733868-Running-Shiny-Server-with-a-Proxy&#34;&gt;https://support.rstudio.com/hc/en-us/articles/213733868-Running-Shiny-Server-with-a-Proxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide is for Ubuntu but I imagine the configuration will work on any Apache server. You’ll just need to figure out what the equivalent terminal commands are for whatever OS you’re using.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scraping the RStudio webinar list</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-03-08-scraping-the-rstudio-webinar-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 18:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-03-08-scraping-the-rstudio-webinar-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I only just found this list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/resources/webinars/&#34;&gt;RStudio webinars&lt;/a&gt;, there’s loads of stuff on there, I really need to plow through a lot of it. What I really wanted was a list of them with links that I could archive and edit and rearrange so I could show which ones I am interested in, which I’ve already watched, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, if you’ve got a problem, and no-one else can help, then maybe you need… The R Team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One weird trick to getting column types right with read_csv</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-02-22-one-weird-trick-to-getting-column-types-right-with-read_csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-02-22-one-weird-trick-to-getting-column-types-right-with-read_csv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using read_csv from the tidyverse is so easy that I didn’t bother to look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/readr/README.html&#34;&gt;readr documentation&lt;/a&gt; for a long time. However, I’m glad I did, because there is, as they say in the click bait world, one weird trick to get your column types right with read_csv. read_csv (or the other delimited file reading functions like read_tsv) does a brilliant job guessing what column types things are but by default it only looks at 1000 rows. Fine for most datasets, but actually I have more than one dataset where the first 1000 rows are missing, which doesn’t help the parser at all. So do it manually and get it right. But what a pain, all that typing, right? Wrong. Just do this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysing runs from the Polar web flow service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-02-09-analysing-runs-from-the-polar-web-flow-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 10:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-02-09-analysing-runs-from-the-polar-web-flow-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, we’re still in New Year’s resolutions territory, so what better time to have a look at using R to analyse data collected from a run? For this analysis I have used the Polar Flow web service to download two attempts at the same &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.org.uk/forestrec/&#34;&gt;Parkrun&lt;/a&gt;, recorded on a Polar M600 (which I love, by the way, if you’re looking for a running/ smartwatch recommendation).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The background to the analysis is in the second of the two runs I thought I was doing really well and was going to crush my PB and it ended up being exactly the same as the previous run, in terms of total time taken, but with my heart rate a lot lower.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Year blog post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-01-26-new-year-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-01-26-new-year-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So my favourite productivity guru, David Allen, he of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; fame, has a suggestion for a New Year review that you should carry out each year. His &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.improvisedlife.com/2012/01/09/david-allens-potent-questions-for-a-new-year/&#34;&gt;suggested structure&lt;/a&gt; can be found here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this is an excellent idea so I have set myself a recurring reminder to do it each year, starting now. And I may as well blog it so I can find it again and anyone else who’s interested can have a read and maybe be inspired to do their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gathering data (wide to long) in the tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-01-22-gathering-data-wide-to-long-in-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 16:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2018-01-22-gathering-data-wide-to-long-in-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I seem to have a pretty severe mental block about the gather() function from dplyr so this is yet another post that to be honest is basically for me to refer to in 6 months when I forget all this stuff. So I’m going to address the mental block I have very specifically and show some code; hopefully it will help someone else out there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So whenever I use gather I put the whole dataframe in. Say I’ve got ten variables. I whack the whole dataframe in and try to pull out just the ones I want using the select() notation at the end of the list of arguments. This DOES NOT MAKE ANY SENSE. You can’t do this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failure to produce pdf with RMarkdown tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-12-20-failure-to-produce-pdf-with-rmarkdown-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 15:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-12-20-failure-to-produce-pdf-with-rmarkdown-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m using tidyverse for everything now, as I’ve mentioned in previous posts, when I want a cup of tea I just run:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;house %&amp;gt;%&#xA;  filter(kitchen == 1) %&amp;gt;%&#xA;  select(tea, kettle) %&amp;gt;%&#xA;  infuse()&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ChrisBeeley/867ffe93f541797e48f3ad195a75efb9&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;(in a gist because the markup makes Hugo go strange) in a vanilla RStudio setup with pdflatex installed&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the code that you get if you set up an RMarkdown project in RStudio and select “compile to LaTeX”, and you want to do some data stuff with the tidyverse package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Font size of code in .Rpres presentations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-12-08-font-size-of-code-in-rpres-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 16:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-12-08-font-size-of-code-in-rpres-presentations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if I even knew about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.rstudio.com/hc/en-us/sections/200130218-R-Presentations&#34;&gt;.Rpres presentation feature&lt;/a&gt; in RStudio v. 0.98 and above. As I think I mentioned I’ve been rather ill for the last couple of years and I’m afraid I kind of fell out of touch with things a bit. Anyway, I’m all better now and I’m going to be giving a talk at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/NottinghamR-Nottingham-R-Users-Group/&#34;&gt;R User Group in Nottingham&lt;/a&gt; (which I love profoundly) so I thought I’d do it this new sexy way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Git commit messages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-11-21-better-git-commit-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 11:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-11-21-better-git-commit-messages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something else I’m trying to be better at is using Git. I did use it, briefly, a few years back but I never quite got the hang of it and I’ve reverted to the bad habit of having MainCode/ and TestingCode/ and TryNewFunction/ folders filled with near identical code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I’m back on the Git wagon again. Atom (see my &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/?p=1023&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;) has beautiful Git integration, as you’d expect since it was built by the GitHub people. It also enforces a couple of conventions with writing Git commit messages, which inspired me on a Google search which led me to this, &lt;a href=&#34;https://chris.beams.io/posts/git-commit/&#34;&gt;a guide to writing better commit messages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ellen Townsend: Small talk saves lives — IMH Blog (Nottingham)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-11-17-ellen-townsend-small-talk-saves-lives-imh-blog-nottingham/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 20:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-11-17-ellen-townsend-small-talk-saves-lives-imh-blog-nottingham/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It sounds much too simple doesn’t it? Making small talk could save a life. But the truth is, it really could. Today SHRG is supporting the campaign launched by the Samaritans. They are asking us all to be courageous and strike up a conversation with someone if we are worried about them at a railway […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://imhblog.wordpress.com/2017/11/17/ellen-townsend-small-talk-saves-lives/&#34;&gt;Ellen Townsend: Small talk saves lives — IMH Blog (Nottingham)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filtering data straight into a plot with tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-09-15-filtering-data-straight-into-a-plot-with-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 09:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-09-15-filtering-data-straight-into-a-plot-with-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m still trying to go full tidyverse, as I believe I mentioned a while back. It’s clearly a highly useful approach, but on top of this I see a load of code in blogs and tutorials that uses a tidy approach. So unless I learn it I’m not going to have a lot of luck reading it. I saw somebody do the following a little while back and I really like it so I thought I’d share it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One editor to rule them all- Atom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-07-02-one-editor-to-rule-them-all-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 09:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-07-02-one-editor-to-rule-them-all-atom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m very happy using RStudio for all my R code. It goes without saying that the support for R coding built into RStudio is phenomenal. If you don’t know loads of cool stuff RStudio does, you’re missing out, but that’s a blog post on its own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve never quite been happy with my choice for other general editing, though. Sometimes I write PHP, HTML, markdown, Python, or something else, and I’ve never really found an editor that I love. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geany.org/&#34;&gt;Geany&lt;/a&gt; is pretty good and that’s what I have been using when I write PHP or HTML. I tended to write markdown in RStudio, which is kind of stupid, since RStudio is an awfully big hammer to crack that nut, but it does support markdown and I’m familiar with RStudio, so I was happy enough doing that. I never really found a Python IDE that I loved. As far as I can tell there isn’t really an RStudio equivalent in the Python world, something so well featured and brilliant that it’s really the only choice unless you have a very particular reason to use something else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lazy tables with R and pander</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-05-23-lazy-tables-with-r-and-pander/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 14:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-05-23-lazy-tables-with-r-and-pander/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the many things I love about R is how gloriously lazy it can help you to be. I’m writing a report at the moment and I need to make lots of tables in R Markdown. I need them to be proportions, expressed as a percentage, rounded to 0 decimal places, and I need to add (%) to each label on the table. That’s a lot of code when you’ve got 8 or 10 tables to draw, so I just made a function that does it. It takes two arguments, the variable you want tabulated, and the order in which you want the table. I need to specify the order manually because the default alphabetical ordering doesn’t work with all of the data that I want, as in the example here. Without ordering manually, the “Less than one year” category appears at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quarters and modulo arithmetic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-04-21-quarters-and-modulo-arithmetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 12:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-04-21-quarters-and-modulo-arithmetic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another post that’s mainly for my benefit when I inevitably forget. I’m working with dates in PHP which, unlike MySQL, does not have a built in quarter function for extracting the quarter from a year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even if it did, one would have to be very careful with it because quarters are actually defined differently in different countries. In the UK, where I am, April to June is the first quarter (and January to March the last). In other countries, including (I think) the US, the first quarter is January to March, and October to December the last.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consuming REST APIs with PHP and CURL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-04-20-consuming-rest-apis-with-php-and-curl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 11:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-04-20-consuming-rest-apis-with-php-and-curl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wasted such a lot of time on this that I must commit it to the internet on the off chance that it helps someone else in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using PHP to consume a RESTful API via CURL and you want to manipulate the data you get back it’s very important that you set CURLOPT_RETURNTRANSFER to true. This allows you to collect the response from the server in a variable. If you don’t set this option it will just echo the return to the screen, which is obviously of no use whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting a grouped plyr::ddply() to dplyr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-04-13-converting-a-grouped-plyrddply-to-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 16:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2017-04-13-converting-a-grouped-plyrddply-to-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going full &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidyverse.org/&#34;&gt;tidyverse&lt;/a&gt; at the moment and so I’m converting my old plyr code to dplyr. It’s been pretty steady going so far, although I had a bit of difficulty converting an instruction using ddply which carried out a function based on a subgrouping within the data. I wrote a toy example to get it right, I may as well share it with the internet in case it helps someone else. If you can’t figure out what I’m talking about with what the function does, just run the code. You’ll see what it is. Easier than explaining in words. The following two functions carry out the same task, the latter is a translation of the former.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Munging Patient Opinion data with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=904/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 11:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=904/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve written a post about using Patient Opinion’s new API, focusing on how to download your data using R but also perhaps useful to those using other languages as a gentle introduction, which can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/?p=886&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on the specific data operations which I perform in R in order to get the data nicely formatted and stored on our server. This may be of interest to those using R who want to do something very similar, much of this code will probably work in a similar context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Querying the Patient Opinion API from R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=886/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 11:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=886/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patientopinion.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Patient Opinion&lt;/a&gt; have a new API out. They are retiring the old API, so you’ll need to transfer over to the new one if you are currently using the old version, but in any case there are a number of advantages to doing so. The biggest one for me is the option to receive results in JSON (or JSONP) rather than XML (although you can still have XML if you want). The old XML output was fiddly and annoying to parse so personally I’m glad to see the back of it (you can see the horrible hacky code I wrote to parse the old version &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/?p=487&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). The JSON comes out beautifully using the built in functions from the R package &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/httr/index.html&#34;&gt;httr&lt;/a&gt; which I shall be using to download and process the data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concatenating text nicely with commas and &amp;#8220;and&amp;#8221;s</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=871/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 15:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=871/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, this blog is quiet at the moment. I can’t even remember if I’ve written this anywhere but I had a liver transplant in May and I’ve been repeatedly hospitalised with complications ever since. So work and life are a little slow. I’m hoping to be back to full health in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was just writing some Shiny code and I have a dynamic text output consisting of one, two, or many pieces of text which needs to have commas and “and”s added to make natural English, like so:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working as a coder at a technology company versus working as a coder in other contexts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=861/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 13:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=861/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was just skimming a &lt;a href=&#34;https://learnpythonthehardway.org/book/advice.html&#34;&gt;book about Python&lt;/a&gt; and I found a rather interesting quote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Programming as a profession is only moderately interesting. It can be a good job, but you could make about the same money and be happier running a fast food joint. You’re much better off using code as your secret weapon in another profession.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People who can code in the world of technology companies are a dime a dozen and get no respect. People who can code in biology, medicine, government, sociology, physics, history, and mathematics are respected and can do amazing things to advance those disciplines.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open document formats and why we need them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=824/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 20:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=824/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whole world is moving to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendocumentformat.org/&#34;&gt;open document formats&lt;/a&gt; for the obvious reason that in order to read and write documents one shouldn’t need to waste money on Microsoft’s increasingly ungainly Office application when perfectly good &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software&#34;&gt;free and open source&lt;/a&gt; alternatives exist (thinking particularly of the mighty &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.libreoffice.org/&#34;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt;). The UK Government has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/open-document-format-odf-guidance-for-uk-government&#34;&gt;formally adopted&lt;/a&gt; an open standard for all of its documents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite this many public bodies in the UK, including the NHS, councils, and many other organisations, continue to use Microsoft’s proprietary formats for documents. It may seem to the casual user that the arguments for proprietary versus open document formats are rather arcane. I would like to tell a story from my own life that illustrates why in actual fact every citizen and certainly every public body should be interested in open document formats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backing up a remote MySQL database on a remote server using cron</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=779/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 15:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=779/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is more a collection of links, really, than a proper blog post, but I just spent quite a while figuring out how all of these different technologies all fit together to do the job I wanted so if you want to do what it says on the tin of this blog post then you should find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have a remote server running a MySQL database. I wish to backup this server daily. I would rather do this on my other remote server than on my local machine because, obviously, my server is always switched on whereas my local machine isn’t. So the task is to dump a MySQL database to a file and upload it to a remote server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make your own HTML tables in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=796/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 14:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=796/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve avoid writing HTML tables by hand in R, reasoning that it would be far too complicated. But the problem with using packages like pander and rmarkdown, much as I love those packages, is you can’t fine tune the outputs. So if a colleague asks you to add little extra touches for a report you can’t really do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So it was a nice surprise to find that it’s actually not that hard. Here’s a table with 3 columns which looks very nice with bootstrap (don’t know what the styling options are on WordPress so it just looks unformatted here)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G&#43;&#43; error compiling on R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=783/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 18:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=783/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was installing R packages (the httpuv package, but I imagine others would generate the same problem) on my Ubuntu server today and I got a very strange error message:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;g++: error: Welcome: No such file or directory&lt;br&gt;&#xA;g++: error: to: No such file or directory&lt;br&gt;&#xA;g++: error: R!: No such file or directory&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a problem with my .Rprofile.site file. That’s why it looks funny, because R is saying “Welcome to R”, but for some reason this is messing with g++. In my case it seemed to be generated by running R as sudo, but I need to do that to make the package library writable. Just invoke R at the terminal with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing files from host machine on virtualbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=769/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 11:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=769/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve really started getting into virtual machines recently. Firstly because I like to try different flavours of Linux and constantly reinstalling partitions is starting to get a bit of a drag, especially when it often takes ages to get the graphical desktop to work because of my silly graphics card. Secondly, and more importantly, because I’m finding if you want to do programming, or especially write about programming, you often need a “clean” system or a system set up a particular way to test things and work on multiple things at once. So the code I write for &lt;a href=&#34;http://shiny.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; is based on the newest 0.12 version. However, my server is all the way back on 0.7 for various reasons to do with browser compatibility. So this means I need a local 0.7 installation to test programs that I’m updating on the server. Or sometimes it can be important to check what the dependencies for your programs are. You may have installed something a year ago that makes everything work beautifully that you’ve long since forgotten about, and if you tell someone else to do what you’re doing it won’t work on their machine. In the Linux world technologies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; which package up whole environments at the operating system level and help you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://deis.com/blog/2015/sailing-past-dependency-hell-with-docker&#34;&gt;manage dependencies&lt;/a&gt; (amongst other things) are starting to spring up and in the R world things like &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.github.io/packrat/&#34;&gt;packrat&lt;/a&gt; roll up packages into bundles in order that all package versions are the same and dependencies satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single file Shiny app to take GET parameters and return date range input boxes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=757/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 14:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=757/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent quite a long time fiddling around with some code for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedback.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/&#34;&gt;feedback website&lt;/a&gt; for which I am responsible for all the reporting so we can distribute custom URLs to individuals who have specific reports they want to run. We use &lt;a href=&#34;http://shiny.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; to do custom reports, the application lives &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedback.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/reports/custom&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and many of the people who run the reports (our staff in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/&#34;&gt;Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust&lt;/a&gt;, mainly) would welcome the ability to have the date range preselected by means of a URL containing GET parameters which they could just click so that the date range is pre-selected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Producing headings in Word files programmatically using knitr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2015-09-01-producing-headings-in-word-files-programmatically-using-knitr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/posts/2015-09-01-producing-headings-in-word-files-programmatically-using-knitr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&#34;http://yihui.name/knitr/&#34;&gt;knitr&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes I have to send people documents in Word. It works beautifully except when I want to produce headings programmatically in code using cat(). This is fine in HTML:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;```&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sapply(headings, function(x){&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  cat(paste0(&amp;#34;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&amp;#34;, x, &amp;#34;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&amp;#34;))&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;  cat(paste0(&amp;#34;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;#34;, rep(&amp;#34;Some text here&amp;#34;, 10), &amp;#34;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;#34;))&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;})&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;```&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, when writing Word .docx files using &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt; the heading tags are not recognised. Well, they’re not printed, so they obviously are recognised, but they don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digikam crashes on startup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=748/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 09:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=748/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be honest, this post is really designed as a reminder to me in case I ever reinstall my OS, but it will probably get a bit of Google juice and could possibly help somebody else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digikam.org/&#34;&gt;Digikam&lt;/a&gt; (a fine piece of software for organising your photos, well worth a look) and you find that it crashes on startup with Linux Mint, then&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: bash; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;sudo apt-get install kdelibs-bin kdelibs5-data kdelibs5-plugins&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convert pdf to text on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=740/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 09:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=740/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had rather an ugly scanned pdf of a very lovely poem over on our &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedback.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/content/wonderful-poem-about-nurses-care-and-compassion-mother-and-baby-unit&#34;&gt;feedback website&lt;/a&gt; so I thought I would try to post the text from it using Optical Character Recognition using &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/tesseract-ocr/&#34;&gt;tesseract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Ubuntu start with:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;``&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install tesseract-ocr imagemagick&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You’ll need to convert the pdf to an image file:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;``&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;convert -density 600 input.pdf output.tif&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and then output to output.txt like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;``&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;tesseract myscan.png out&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips for five years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=731/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 09:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=731/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw some wonderful tweets the other day where the author gave their former naive self some time-travelling advice from their present self about how best to get started with programming. I did intend to keep the link but sadly my filing system has failed and it’s fallen through the cracks. I’m grateful to the author, in any case, for inspiring this post, written on the fifth anniversary of my own initial foray into the world of programming. I will give myself five pieces of advice for five years, also because five is a nice round-ish number.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&amp;#8217;t apologise- it&amp;#8217;s just feedback</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=726/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 09:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=726/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m cross posting this to my team’s blog which can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://involvementvolunteeringexperience.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to bring together my two worlds of programming and Linux-geekery with the Involvement and experience in UK health services which I use programming and Linux-geekery for in my job. Here it is, a story from a meal out in a pub and the lessons the NHS might learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I witnessed a rather amusing event after a meal in a pub last week, but thinking about it the next day I thought perhaps there are some lessons in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Lucida Console on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=722/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 15:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=722/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been a horribly long time since I blogged anything. There’s another small chaos generator in the house and he and his older brother are keeping me pretty busy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is a quick post to solve a problem which appears to have no Google Juice at all- downloading Lucida Console for Linux. If you want Lucida fonts generally there’s some stuff &lt;a href=&#34;http://askubuntu.com/questions/98579/how-do-i-get-lucida-fonts&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but at least when I tried it there was no Lucida Console. There are various bits of outdated and broken links on the subject, and I’m pretty sure one of the sites I was visiting tried to give me a Windows virus, so be careful out there, nonetheless I have found and installed it successfully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Primum non nocere- gathering feedback data in the NHS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=717/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 22:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=717/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the bits of the internet where I hang out is alive with debate around &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/jan/29/a-e-miscarriage-nhs-text&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; comment piece in The Guardian. I would advise you to click through to read it because I can’t give a good summary of how hard-hitting it is but, in summary, it describes a couple who had exemplary service at an A + E department when they suffered a miscarriage but were then very distressed when they received a follow up text the next day asking them to rate their experience of A + E using the NHS’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nhs.uk/NHSEngland/AboutNHSservices/Pages/nhs-friends-and-family-test.aspx&#34;&gt;Friends and Family Test&lt;/a&gt; (how likely are you to recommend this service to others: Extremely likely… etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I did it! I edited some open sourced code!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=710/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 21:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=710/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do try to promote the benefits of open source wherever I go, and one of these many benefits is, of course, the ability of endusers or intermediate parties to modify the source code to make changes to the software. A couple of times I have been dismissed by members of the closed source contingent who mock the idea that individuals who work outside of the IT world (e.g. in healthcare, my own area) would sit down and modify or even read reams of source code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All hail the mighty Cron- setting up cron jobs and a mail server to collect their output logs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=703/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 11:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=703/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At a certain point, everyone with a penchant for databases and Linux is going to want to make use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/CronHowto&#34;&gt;cron&lt;/a&gt;, whether it’s to back up their data, run maintenance on certain fields of a database, or something else (in my case, do a huge pull of MySQL tables and format ready to drop nicely into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://shiny.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; application).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cron is, quite simply, a little pixie who lives on your server and executes scripts at times you determine: every day at midnight, every Wednesday morning, every 6 hours on weekdays, you name it, cron does it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Querying Google analytics data with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=696/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 14:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=696/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is in response to a question on Twitter, but it may be of interest to others. I produced a Shiny app for querying Google Analytics data for my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.packtpub.com/web-development/web-application-development-r-using-shiny&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;. The data on the live version which lives &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net:8080/shiny/GA/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is automatically pulled in via the API each time the application is run. That code cannot live on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisBeeley&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; because it needs the username and password for the API. So I’m reproducing it here. It’s very simple and is based on the wonderful R package rga which can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skardhamar/rga&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously the XXXXXXXs have got real things in the real version, this is the redacted version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book review: PHP Cookbook by David Sklar and Adam Trachtenberg</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=689/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 12:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=689/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a book review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.com/pub/reviewproduct/1911&#34;&gt;PHP Cookbook&lt;/a&gt; by David Sklar, and Adam Trachtenberg.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I received this book free under O’Reilly’s Reader Review Program.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a very comprehensive book indeed. I’m relatively new to PHP programming and I used this book in two different ways. Firstly, as a straightforward cover to cover read, and secondly, as a bit of practice and to make this review a bit more realistic, to help me write a little toy application that I am developing in idle moments in the hope that I can scale it up and use it in my job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source vs. commercial off the shelf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=682/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 17:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=682/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A government department in Australia reports saving very large amounts of money by shunning paid for proprietary software and implementing their own version with R (&lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.itnews.com.au/News/390687,what-immigration-did-with-just-1m-and-open-source-software.aspx&#34;&gt;link to story&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you follow the link they have some comments with a person who works at SAS who naturally talks down the benefits of free and open source software such as R (but then they would, wouldn’t they?). They report “He said the true cost of the supposedly free software can actually be quite substantial, when human resources and maintenance of the software is factored in”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Supercommunicator by Frank J. Pietrucha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=671/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 14:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=671/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a book review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780814433683.do&#34;&gt;Supercommunicator by Frank J. Pietrucha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I received this book free as part of O’Reilly’s reader review program.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s a fact oft-acknowledged that books about communication and especially about grammar fall at the hurdles they themselves set, with books about grammar often containing solecisms and books about communication including leaden or otherwise dreadful prose. Even with this in mind, this is not a good book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make your own Twitter ticker using PHP, CSS3, and JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=657/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 21:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=657/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made a little Twitter ticker for work the other day, which will fetch posts with a particular hashtag and then animate them marquee style across the screen, I thought I may as well share it here. This version will fetch the last 100 tweets to the #rstats hashtag, remove the retweeets, and then show up to 50 animated across the screen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the Twitter authentication PHP magic is stolen from &lt;a href=&#34;http://140dev.com/twitter-api-programming-blog/twitter-api-ebook-single-user-twitter-oauth-programming/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New guest post at Online behaviour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=654/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 09:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=654/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just had a guest post published at Online Behaviour, about visualising Google Analytics data using R and Shiny, which can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://online-behavior.com/analytics/shiny&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Learning PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, and CSS, 2nd Edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=644/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 17:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=644/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I received this ebook free under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.com/reviews/&#34;&gt;O’Reilly Reader Review Programme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920023487.do&#34;&gt;Learning PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, and CSS, 2nd Edition&lt;/a&gt; by Robin Nixon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can tell by the title this is a big book that covers a lot of material. There is a decent treatment of PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, and CSS within this book. When I came to it I knew nothing about PHP, a little MySQL, a smidgen of JavaScript, and a little bit of CSS and could follow each of the sections without too much difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn to program, or loads of other stuff, for free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=641/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 22:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=641/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are more and more free sources of free sources of courses in programming and more besides. I’ve just come across a slew so I thought I’d record them for my benefit and yours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codecademy.com/&#34;&gt;Code academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.khanacademy.org/&#34;&gt;Khan academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edx.org/&#34;&gt;EdX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://swirlstats.com/&#34;&gt;Swirl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web application development with R using Shiny new version of code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=631/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 20:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=631/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new version of Shiny (0.9) is wonderful, hopefully I will talk about it again soon, but it does break the code in my book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/web-application-development-with-r-using-shiny/book&#34;&gt;Web application development with R using Shiny&lt;/a&gt;. It’s only a small difference, the selectInput() function used to ask for preselected elements to be given as the name of a list (i.e. the friendly version that appears to users in the UI, “Egg Salad”) whereas now it asks for the actual value (“eggSalad”, e.g.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiny server working on Windows based virtual machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=624/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 21:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=624/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working in the NHS as I do, which runs all of its IT on Windows, I’d always despaired of being able to get &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/server/&#34;&gt;Shiny Server&lt;/a&gt; working. However, I went to see the IT department and they have very kindly given me access to a virtual machine with Ubuntu 12.04.04 LTS running on it. It’s completely firewalled from the internet and is only visible from within the network, which is quite useful because it means I can put up things on it which are not for public consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful R functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=530/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 13:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=530/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today seems as good a day as any to start archiving all the useful R functions I see scattered around the internet. And here seems as good a place as any to do it since I can see it and so can anyone else who is interested. Two to start, will add more as I get them. Credit to original authors, follow the link.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Removing whitespace&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;trimws()&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7963898/extracting-the-last-n-characters-from-a-string-in-r&#34;&gt;Extract the last n characters of a string&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Produce Word documents, web pages, and pdfs in R quickly and easily</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=609/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 13:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=609/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started using R in about 2009 &lt;a href=&#34;http://users.stat.umn.edu/~geyer/Sweave/&#34;&gt;reproducible research&lt;/a&gt; was a complete eye-opener for me. Statistical analyses should be reproducible both by the author of them and by the scientific community and by embedding the analysis and outputting code within a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-cs-faculty.stanford.edu/~uno/lp.html&#34;&gt;literate programming&lt;/a&gt; framework such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweave&#34;&gt;Sweave&lt;/a&gt; this was possible. Nearly everything I produce now, whether for regular reports on patient experience for the NHS Trust for which I work or for scientific papers is reproducible. These tools have saved me (and therefore my employer) hundreds of hours and they are all totally free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a new Linux install, quickstart guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=593/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 14:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=593/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another post which is designed both to help me as an aide-memoire and also to help anyone else out there who wants to set up a new Linux install quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the many, many things I love about Linux is the way that you can just tear down your OS any time you like and start using a different one. Having said that, I must admit to having had some long weekends and evenings when my installation has gone kaput fiddling around trying to get everything working. I have now streamlined the process and can set up a new Ubuntu-based distribution in probably no more than about 45 minutes. My Linux career has only been from Ubuntu to the Ubuntu-based Mint so far, I have tried to use Fedora but sadly my ridiculously powerful NVidia graphics card left over from my (whisper it) Windoze days does not appear to play nicely at all with Fedora. Going to have a go with Fedora 20 some time, you never know your luck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buy my book from #Packt in the Buy One, Get One Free sale bit.ly/1j26nPN #Packt2k</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=603/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 21:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=603/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/?utm_source=referral&amp;amp;utm_medium=marketingPR&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2000thTitle&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/2000th-Book-Home-Page-Banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;2000th-Book-Home-Page-Banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My publisher is having a sale, buy one get on free on all ebooks, so if you wish to buy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/web-application-development-with-r-using-shiny/book&#34;&gt;my book&lt;/a&gt; or indeed a book about something else, go check it out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/?utm_source=referral&amp;amp;utm_medium=marketingPR&amp;amp;utm_campaign=2000thTitle&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My PhD thesis is online finally</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=590/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 10:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=590/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To my great shame, I never published the findings from my PhD (Daily behavioural ratings: what can behavioural observation tell us about psychopathy, personality disorder and violence risk in secure psychiatric settings?) in any journals, by the time I’d finished I was so busy with my new job that I just never got round to it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The least I can do is host the thesis on my server in case it proves of use to anyone, and I have added it to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/website/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; today, link to file &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/website/ChrisBeeleyThesis_WithCorrections.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Doing Data Science: Straight Talk from the Frontline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=578/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 17:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=578/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Book review&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Doing Data Science: Straight Talk from the Frontline By Cathy O’Neil, Rachel Schutt&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Publisher: O’Reilly Media&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I received a free electronic copy of this book to review as part of O’Reilly’s Reader Review Program&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book seems to be everywhere at the moment, largely, I imagine, because there’s a gaping hole in the market for such a book. Indeed, there’s a gaping hole in the market, it seems, for everything to do with data science, from books and courses to the actual people themselves. Famously, the world toiled away without even a Wikipedia entry for data science until the relatively recent past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boss of year of code can&amp;#8217;t code- do we all need to be able to code?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=571/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 21:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=571/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As many of you will be aware, the Twittersphere was recently ignited by Lottie Dexter (&lt;a href=&#34;http://politicalscrapbook.net/2014/02/tory-boss-of-government-coding-education-initiative-cant-code-lottie-dexter/&#34;&gt;Year of code boss can’t code&lt;/a&gt;) and her car crash performance on Newsnight. I don’t have much to add to what has already been said apart from to note with sadness yet another typical example of a public servant being involved with technology of which they have no comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Paxman expressed cynicism within the interview regarding the idea that all people need to be able to code, and by extension that all children need to be taught coding. I think this betrays an understanding of what it means to “be able to code”. I would like to illustrate this with a couple of examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pick up a copy of my book or another ebook for $5 #Packt$5 #ebookbonanza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=564/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 12:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=564/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The publisher of my book, Packt, is having an ebook sale:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following on from the success of last year’s festive offer, the publisher will be celebrating the holiday season with an even bigger $5 Bonanza.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From December 19th, customers will be able to get any eBook or Video from Packt for just $5. This sale covers every title in the 1700+ range and customers can grab as many as they like until January 3rd 2014 – more information is available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/1jdCr2W&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/1jdCr2W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clearly Better For Analytics and Graphics (My LondonR talk- Developing with Shiny for the Web)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=554/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 21:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=554/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.londonr.org/&#34;&gt;LondonR&lt;/a&gt; group last night about using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; and particularly about integrating it with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery to go nicely with other web content. Appropriately enough, therefore, I made the whole talk using HTML. Thanks to Romain Francois for his excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/highlight/index.html&#34;&gt;highlight&lt;/a&gt; package (surely it should be called highlightR, though?) with which I did the HTML for the highlighting of R syntax and to &lt;a href=&#34;http://tohtml.com/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; website with which I highlighted the HTML, JavaScript and jQuery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The internet platform of the future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=551/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 09:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=551/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently sent the following to the New Statesman in response to a piece they recently carried which weighed up the likely fortunes of Google, Facebook, and Apple, and asked which would be the internet platform of the future. It is quite obvious to me that we already have the internet platform of the future, and it’s called Linux. They ran it, edited, in the letters page, but they don’t publish letters online so here, for the first time, live and unplugged, is the unexpurgated version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free and open source software. Come for the free, stay for the awesome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=537/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=537/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just wrote this for the Institute of Mental Health &lt;a href=&#34;http://imhblog.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; so I thought I may as well cross-post here. I promise I will talk about something other than Shiny soon 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open source software refers to software whose code is available for anybody to view, revise and reuse. This should be contrasted with closed or proprietary code which is known only to the manufacturer, and who will often charge a fee for individuals to use the software (for example, Microsoft Word, or Adobe Photoshop).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick p-values for publication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=520/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 06:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=520/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m afraid this is just from a lecture from the school of the totally obvious, but for some unfathomable reason I’ve never got round to doing it. I’m not even telling you the code so much as just saying “you should definitely do this, it’s very easy”. I got the time back after writing one paper and I constantly have to fiddle around with p-values so I imagine I shall save many hours each year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book launch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=511/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 19:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=511/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My book has just come out, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/web-application-development-with-r-using-shiny/book&#34;&gt;Web Application Development with R using Shiny&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an introduction to the marvellous &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; from the wonderful people at RStudio. Although the online documentation for Shiny does cover most of the things you might want to do with it the people who approached me about writing the book thought that having a more comprehensive guide with some worked examples would be useful. And I was inclined to agree. So I wrote the book in 3 months, which was one of the most brilliant and awful experiences of my entire life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patient Opinion data made easy with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=487/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 10:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=487/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not be aware, I recently helped on the data side of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/&#34;&gt;Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust’s&lt;/a&gt; feedback website which lives &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedback.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/reports/custom&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Part of this work was collecting the data we receive from the Trust-wide patient survey and bringing it in with other sources of feedback, including stories from our friends over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patientopinion.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Patient Opinion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a long time I’ve queried their data using their API (documentation is &lt;a href=&#34;%E2%80%9Dhttps://www.patientopinion.org.uk/info/api-docs%E2%80%9D&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and fiddled around with it a bit, but my XML was never quite up to doing a proper extract and getting the data into the same structure as the rest of our patient experience data. The job sort of got shelved under “A computer program could do this, nobody has time to write the computer program, maybe a human will do it” which to be honest is quite a large shelf groaning with the weight of a lot of stuff at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some examples of Shiny with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=481/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 10:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=481/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s becoming rather &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt;-centric, this blog, I know, but I just put some little demos about how to use Shiny with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery, just some toy examples with links to source, up on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/website/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So if you’re interested in Shiny go have a look. Each has a link to the interactive version and the source. Do note that there are easier/ better ways of doing some of these things (row highlighting can be done in CSS rather than jQuery, e.g.); these are really just for educational purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiny widget demo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=474/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 16:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you using the brilliant &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; package in R, I’ve built a little toy to help you learn/ remember the main widget types and the type of values they return. Code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ChrisBeeley/6571951&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and it’s running on my Shiny Server &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net:8080/shiny/shinywidgetdemo/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/4474_02_09.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/4474_02_09.png&#34; alt=&#34;4474_02_09&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy/ find useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix on Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=467/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 23:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=467/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One for Linux users forced to use Citrix to log in to their corporate email, such as myself. I’d long given up trying to get Citrix to work on Ubuntu 12.04 on my laptop, but a recent success with 13.04 on my main computer led me to have another go. I followed the instructions here &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/CitrixICAClientHowTo&#34;&gt;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/CitrixICAClientHowTo&lt;/a&gt;, got some weird error message, followed the instructions here &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.citrix.com/thread.jspa?threadID=306353&amp;amp;tstart=0&#34;&gt;http://forums.citrix.com/thread.jspa?threadID=306353&amp;amp;tstart=0&lt;/a&gt; and BOOM, I was in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s Linux’s super-awesome hot breath you can feel on your neck, Windoze.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#8217;s up with chrisbeeley.net?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=462/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 17:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=462/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had my own server for a little while now, with a very scabby and unattractive webpage on it, some Java I haven’t got round to turning into an applet, a couple of random Shiny apps, and that’s about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m very busy at the moment writing a book so I’m afraid I haven’t really had time to work on any of these side projects. I have, however, done loads of cool things with the actual server, so I thought I might mention these. Having your own server is like all the best things in life, once you’ve got it you don’t know how you ever got on without it. So, what are all the exciting things that my server does?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Department for redundancy department results of staff survey questionnaire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=454/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 14:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=454/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just received the following in a local newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s reasonably clear, so it passes the first test, but really the decimal places are redundant, as are the frequency counts. Much nicer in a bar chart, of course:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;barplot(c(23.6, 24.2, 26.4, 20.2, 6.2),&#xA;    names.arg = c(&amp;#34;Not at all&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Not entirely&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Ambivalent&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Somewhat&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Very&amp;#34;),&#xA;    col = heat.colors(5), ylab=&amp;#34;%&amp;#34;, main = &amp;#34;Happiness with new PDPR procedure&amp;#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiny application in a morning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=414/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 08:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=414/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sort of apropos of nothing, really, this, but I was doing some research with some colleagues the other day and to help out I built a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/&#34;&gt;shiny&lt;/a&gt; application in a morning. Munging the data etc. took ages as it always does but once I actually had everything clean and tidy and working laying an interface on top was the easy bit. What a fantastic tool it really is, completely changed the way we work with data now we can just throw stuff on the internet and let people play around just in the morning. My sincere thanks to all the devs at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;RStudio.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change we need to see in Government and public service IT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=412/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 14:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=412/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of material here, including a 22 minute talk, but if you’re even remotely interested in IT in government and public services then please have a look here (you can get all three by clicking through, but I’ve extracted each link for you).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://digital.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/2012/02/02/gov-uk-truly-open-platform/&#34;&gt;gov.uk a truly open platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://digital.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/2011/11/02/the-unacceptable/&#34;&gt;The unacceptable in government IT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://digital.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/2011/10/25/listen-to-chris-chant-talking-about-g-cloud/&#34;&gt;Chris Chant on the future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&amp;#8217;s alive!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=405/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 19:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=405/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it finally launched today, the patient feedback website that we created as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.institute.nhs.uk/innovation/spread_and_adoption/nhs_patient_feedback_challenge.html&#34;&gt;Patient Feedback Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The evaluation section was part of a partnership with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/get-involved/involvement-team/&#34;&gt;Involvement Centre&lt;/a&gt; of Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust and the web design agency &lt;a href=&#34;http://numiko.com/&#34;&gt;Numiko&lt;/a&gt; to build a website which can help us to collect feedback data, summarise and report on it and share the actions and learning which have resulted. Go have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedback.nottinghamshirehealthcare.nhs.uk/&#34;&gt;look&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part of the philosophy of the feedback challenge was that the good practice should be “spreadable” and the website is all built using free and open source technologies (Linux servers, all data and graphs processed using &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; etc.). We plan to roll it out in as many Trusts as possible and will charge a small sum for redesigns and changes to data processing which will allow us to repurpose it for different Trusts as well as supporting further development of the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UK government pays me to write open source all day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=402/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 11:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=402/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open source is creeping into government and my area, health, bit by bit (no pun intended!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alas, the reblogs don’t work in my new self-hosted WordPress. Here’s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.quickpeople.co.uk/2013/05/17/the-uk-government-pays-me-to-write-open-source-all-day/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Survivorship Bias</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=400/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 08:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=400/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not the usual topic of this blog, but a great post and well worth a read. My old reblogs are not working now I’ve self hosted, link &lt;a href=&#34;http://youarenotsosmart.com/2013/05/23/survivorship-bias/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cool graph in 5 seconds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=398/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 11:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cool graph in 5 seconds. Open R. Type&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;library(rgl)&#xA;&#xA;with(mtcars, plot3d(wt, disp, mpg, col=&amp;amp;quot;red&amp;amp;quot;, size=3))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spin the graph with your mouse. Cool!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Hat-tip to the mighty &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.statmethods.net/graphs/scatterplot.html&#34;&gt;Quick-R&lt;/a&gt; from whom I stole the code)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does your maternity leave look like?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=380/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=380/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://evolutionaryparenting.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/17998_588577684488055_1638250904_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;What does your maternity leave look like?&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now THIS is a visualisation- the same child photographed at ages corresponding to statutory paid maternity leave in different countries&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Information is Actionable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=378/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=378/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brilliant post on the conflict between the needs of analysts and decision makers… with cats! Genius post on a genius blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://statswithcats.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/all-information-is-actionable/&#34;&gt;Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data in the NHS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=371/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=371/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a little piece for an information pack related to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.institute.nhs.uk/innovation/spread_and_adoption/nhs_patient_feedback_challenge.html&#34;&gt;Patient Feedback Challenge&lt;/a&gt; so I thought I may as well share it here. I’m a little rushed so I won’t hyperlink the references, apologies for this they are all at the bottom in plain text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NHS data systems are, quite naturally, built around very strict data management systems which emphasise the security of data and ensuring accountability of data loss or misuse. This is right and proper. However, very frequently, clinicians, managers, auditors and evaluators do not need to access highly sensitive personal information. In certain cases, information can be shared freely over the internet, as with the data collected on patient experience within the Patient Feedback Challenge (survey responses, Patient Opinion stories, and specific extracts from the PALS database).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unstable net promoter scores</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=303/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 17:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=303/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you work in the NHS you’ll know that the “net promoter score” (aka the friends and family test- “would you recommend this service to family and friends?”) is coming to NHS services, indeed it’s hit the headlines with the coalition government promoting its use in the face of some pretty stiff opposition (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/health-and-families/health-news/health-experts-reject-friends-and-family-test-8440238.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have never been all that convinced by it, particularly the way the score is calculated by subtracting the percentage of detractors (those who would not recommend or unlikely to) from the percentage of promoters (those who would recommend). We’ve started using it in our survey and I have had a query because one area’s scores are jumping around a lot. I thought it was high time I looked at the actual scores. We don’t use a 10 point scale as many do, we use a 5 point scale, with the points being equal to “Extremely unlikely”, “Unlikely”, “Neither”, “Likely”, and “Very likely”. Net promoter is calculated by taking the proportion of “Very likely”s and subtracting the proportion of the bottom 3 categories summed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bottom-up creation of data-driven capabilities: show don’t tell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=302/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 11:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=302/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fantastic post on how interactive analysis can help sell data-driven answers within an organisation. Time will tell if I can achieve similar things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://houseofstones.me/2012/12/05/bottom-up-creation-of-data-driven-capabilities-show-dont-tell/&#34;&gt;Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiny app running at last</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=293/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 21:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=293/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently taking part in the NHS Institute for Innovation supported Patient Feedback challenge with colleagues at Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust. We’re delivering our patient feedback in a web system and I have been working with the web developers, the lovely people over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://numiko.com/#/home&#34;&gt;Numiko&lt;/a&gt;, they’re doing all the web type stuff and I’m writing R code, running over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rforge.net/FastRWeb/&#34;&gt;FastRWeb&lt;/a&gt;, which is fantastic and will get a well deserved blog post some time soon.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In order to make sure that my code keeps pace with the interface they design and there’s no nasty surprises when the launch of the website gets near I’ve been doing some prototyping with the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; package from the amazing people over at RStudio, whose IDE I sincerely love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>But I do want to be data (cross posted)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=255/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 20:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=255/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a guest piece on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patientopinion.org.uk/blog/post/2012/09/17/guest-blog-but-i-do-want-to-be-data.aspx&#34;&gt;Patient Opinion Blog&lt;/a&gt; which is cross-posted below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare scientists will universally recognise the dominance of quantitative methodology over qualitative methodology, with the oft-qutoed hierarchy of evidence featuring such quantitative behemoths as meta-analysis and RCT at the top and qualitative methods further down, rather sniffily described as “Case reports” or “Case series”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a rather hardcore quantitative scientist myself with a great deal of good feeling towards my qualitative brethren, it was with joy and horror that I read Paul’s recent &lt;a href=&#34;//www.patientopinion.org.uk/blog/post/2012/07/06/i-done28099t-want-to-be-data-i-want-a-conversation.aspx%E2%80%9D&#34;&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; on the Patient Opinion blog “I don’t want to be data, I want a conversation”, which flips the usual dominance relationship on its head and champions qualitative over quantitative methods. Paul argues that the NHS needs to “step outside its mindset” and stop using words like “captured” and “mined” in regard to patient feedback which should be treated, first and foremost, as a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super easy heatmaps of postcodes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=239/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 08:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=239/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whatever I want to do, there are always intrepid explorers who’ve been there and blogged it, and so the satisfaction of my long held desire to get to know more about how Nottinghamshire Healthcare’s services are spread geographically has been wonderfully expedited by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.revolutionanalytics.com/2012/07/making-beautiful-maps-in-r-with-ggmap.html&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; amazing &lt;a href=&#34;http://stevendkay.wordpress.com/2010/04/21/plotting-postcode-density-heatmaps-in-r/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Special thanks, of course, go to David Kahle and Hadley Wickham, progenitors of the mighty &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggmap/index.html&#34;&gt;ggmap&lt;/a&gt; package and also to the fine folk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geonames.org/&#34;&gt;geonames&lt;/a&gt; who freely distribute postcodes from around the world in .csv format.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easy tables for publication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=230/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 13:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=230/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m writing for a journal article today and it’s the familiar problem of how to export all of the beautiful tables and graphs from LaTeX to Word (using R, of course).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s surprisingly easy to get a table from R into Word (or Open Office, or…). Just export the table to a text file and use tab-delimiting:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;write.table(mytable1, &amp;#34;Summary.txt&amp;#34;, sep=&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then simply copy the table into the file, select “Convert text to table”, make sure “tab-delimiting” is selected, which it probably is, and voila.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A joke about R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=219/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 08:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=219/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m so sorry, I’ve come across an R joke I must share. If you don’t care about R, look away now because this post is definitely not for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A scientist and a statistician are working together in the office. The scientist says to the statistician “Which is the fastest way to identify non-zero elements in an array using R?”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The statistician replies “Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“No, which is the fastest way?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R-Uni (A List of Free R Tutorials and Resources in University webpages)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=218/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 19:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=218/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pairach.com/2012/02/26/r-tutorials-from-universities-around-the-world/&#34;&gt;List&lt;/a&gt; of R tutorials for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great analogue visualisation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=215/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 10:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=215/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps another chapter in the infographics versus data graphics debate, a truly eye-catching visualisation of sugar contents in different drinks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wp.me/p240RE-cd&#34;&gt;Rethink Your Drink!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallelising with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=209/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 10:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=209/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fitting some generalised linear mixed effects models with 400,000 rows or so and it takes a while even on my quad core 3.4Ghz behemoth. The time has come for me to learn how to use multiple cores with R. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/parallel/doc/parallel.pdf&#34;&gt;parallel&lt;/a&gt; library which comes with the new-ish R 2.14 makes it pretty easy. For my purposes, all I needed to do was pop all of my calculations in a list and then call &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rforge.net/doc/packages/multicore/mclapply.html&#34;&gt;mclapply&lt;/a&gt; on them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick R tip- making scripts work across OS&amp;#8217;s</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=205/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 14:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=205/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick thought for newbies to R. I have spent four years loading in data like this&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;mydatafirst=read.csv(&amp;#34;D:\Dropbox\R-files\Project1\etc.&amp;#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;on my Windows machine and like this&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: r; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;mydatafirst=read.csv(&amp;#34;/home/chris/Dropbox/R-files/Project1/etc.&amp;#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;on my Linux machine. I would comment out the one I wasn’t using at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s fine for a while but once you start reading multiple dataframes (particularly if they’re not all loaded at the start) it gets very fiddly and annoying. Don’t do this. Just set your working directory. You can do it manually:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr John Milton &amp;#8211; Your days are numbered: Measuring clinical performance in mental health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=203/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 08:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=203/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://imhblog.wordpress.com/2012/03/30/dr-john-milton-your-days-are-numbered-measuring-clinical-performance-in-mental-health/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; re: Moneyball and a clinician’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excellent post about R base graphics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=199/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 12:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=199/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a keen user of the base graphics functionality in &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; (and you should be) then you’ll love this excellent summary of some of the useful and esoteric options within:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://isomorphismes.tumblr.com/post/19688088245/base-plot-r-options-par/&#34;&gt;Click!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Because it&amp;#8217;s Friday- animated graphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=189/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 12:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=189/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been analysing some data and we’re a bit unsure, as we often are, as to its quality. We have a variety of clinicians rating C.tot and R.tot over a four year period for a set of patients. To summarise, there was some concern that people are rating C.tot consistently and well but not so with R.tot (I’m not going to explain the variables or where they come from because it’s not relevant and it’s an internal dataset we’re not ready to share yet).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualization series: Insight from Cleveland and Tufte on plotting numeric data by groups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=187/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 13:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=187/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wonderful post about visualisation and The Problem with Pie Charts (I found a 3D pie chart in a Joint Strategic Needs Assessment this morning).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wp.me/p1RNsv-1a&#34;&gt;Visualization series: Insight from Cleveland and Tufte on plotting numeric data by groups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazing video- Inventing on principle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=182/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 15:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=182/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just seen an amazing video, Brett Victor talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/36579366&#34;&gt;Inventing on Principle.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It should be of great interest to programmers and creatives and indeed anyone who needs or wants to come up with new and exciting ideas (everyone, in other words). If you’re not a programmer, stick with the video because he broadens out the discussion a lot a third of the way in. And if you are, just get stuck in and watch. You won’t regret it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stupidest pie chart of the year 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=171/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 11:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=171/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just been looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.infoadvisors.com/index.php/2011/12/22/stupidest-bar-chart-of-2011-congrats-klout/&#34;&gt;Stupidest bar chart of the year 2011&lt;/a&gt; and I’ve been inspired to submit my Stupidest pie chart of the year 2011. I won’t say from where I obtained it and I’ve drawn the data myself to save from annoying the original authors. And here it is (click to enlarge):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/rplot01.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/rplot01.png?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Stupidest pie chart of the year, 2011&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It represents the amount of maternity and paternity leave available in different countries. Pie charts are often not a very good idea, but in this case they are the worst possible idea. Pie charts should be used when the whole pie has some meaning. A whole customer base, individuals living in Nottinghamshire, something like that. The whole of these pies represents- what? The total amount of leave in these countries. This has no real world meaning at all, and the whole point of the pie chart is lost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Year&amp;#8217;s resolutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=166/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=166/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again, so what do I need to keep doing or do differently this year?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Keep being organised with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;. I found recently that I was processing so many bits of paper and information that I just gave up. Only the most important stuff got stored in my brain, the rest was discarded. Having started using Evernote and guided by Getting Things Done I have a massive brain pack to store everything I can’t use at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complex surveys in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=159/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 14:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=159/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/books.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/books.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;books&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I carried out what I thought was going to be a very simple piece of work the other day, slicing up some of the questions from a publicly available dataset in order to compare Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust with some other sites based on particular features of interest. I will post that work some other time, for now for those who are interested the source code is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisBeeley/Survey-of-mental-health-services&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I thought I would share my experience with the book which helped me through this work, which is &lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=L96ludyhFBsC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=gbs_ge_summary_r&amp;amp;cad=0#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick presentations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=147/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 16:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick one from me today, lots of deadlines colliding, which is handy because that’s what this post is about. I’ve been experimenting with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beamer_(LaTeX)&#34;&gt;beamer&lt;/a&gt; class for LaTeX, with Sweave, which is another way of saying that I’ve been trying to save time producing slides for presentations directly from code as analysed by R.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The syntax is very simple, open a document with:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;documentclass{beamer}&lt;br&gt;&#xA;usetheme{Berlin}&lt;br&gt;&#xA;title{Title goes here}&lt;br&gt;&#xA;author{Chris Beeley}&lt;br&gt;&#xA;date{today}&lt;br&gt;&#xA;begin{document}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 06:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to publish as much of my work as I can on the internet, where the people who own the data agree (my little bit of the website is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.institutemh.org.uk/-about-us-/our-evaluation-service&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) but very often I can’t publish the data because of issues with ongoing projects, other publications, various levels of confidentiality of data, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I’ve decided to try to simulate the data whenever there is an issue with publication. It’s very easy and it’s an excellent way for me to be able to show people my work without any of the issues that come from showing real data. The code is below, it comes in two parts for the first set of variables because we fiddled with the questionnaire a bit after Time 8 in the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robin Hood marathon results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=108/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 16:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=108/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran the Robin Hood marathon yesterday in a decent-ish 4 hours and 13 minutes, which is my best yet. Naturally, I was curious to see how my fellow runners fared, and so I have scraped the times from a pdf and summarised them using R and ggplot2.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I ran to support the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Disaster Emergency Committee, because of the East Africa Appeal, so if you would like to support this very worthy cause then please go &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justgiving.com/Chris-Beeley&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misleading means and medians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=99/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 06:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=99/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://exploringdatablog.blogspot.com/2011/08/some-additional-thoughts-on-useless.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; excellent blog there is an interesting discussion about times when means and medians can be deceptive, particularly in the case where two variables with equal means have very different distributions. I chimed in myself and mentioned some of the examples which I come across in my work. Here is a particularly egregious example, measurement of self-esteem in patients on psychiatric wards in England and Belgium-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;England mean&lt;br&gt;&#xA;3.4&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Belgium mean&lt;br&gt;&#xA;3.2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;England median&lt;br&gt;&#xA;3.3&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Belgium median&lt;br&gt;&#xA;3.2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;England sd&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1.2&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Belgium sd&lt;br&gt;&#xA;0.9&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>useR day four and beginner&amp;#8217;s odfWeave</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2011 07:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a bit late with the report from the last day of the useR conference, I was very busy Thursday getting home and catching up with the housework on Friday. I once again favoured sessions about graphics and best in show must go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://4dpiecharts.com/2011/08/17/user2011-easy-interactive-ggplots-talk/&#34;&gt;Easy interactive ggplots&lt;/a&gt;, particularly for a bit of a coding novice like myself. I’m going to take some of the ideas from this talk and use them at work, it will blow everyone’s mind (well, doing it for free with blow everyone’s mind, anyway) so a big thank you to Richie for sharing his ideas and his code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>useR day three</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=83/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 19:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=83/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last post perhaps was a bit over-long on extraneous detail and bits of R-commands that most readers will either know backwards or have no interest in, and today’s learning sheet is over double the length of yesterday’s, so let’s really do one thing I learned today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned today was about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rtexttools.com/&#34;&gt;RTextTools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; package which sounds like a great way of classifying textual data. I’ve already had a go with some text stuff in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeleyimh.wordpress.com/2011/08/02/fun-with-wordclouds/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; but I hadn’t really thought about the whole data mining/ machine learning thing all that seriously until today. I do wonder whether this would have applications to the patient survey (900 responses a quarter, and actually now I think of it we have about 1500 from early in its life that were never classified). There is a person who codes the responses as they come in, and I don’t need or want to take that job off him, because clearly a person is always going to be better than a machine at classifying text, but if I could prototype it then one intriguing possibility would be raised. It would enable us to change the coding system. We set the whole thing up quite quickly and I did rather think we were stuck with the coding system forever (since we don’t want to recode 6000+ rows) but if the computer can do it reasonably well then we could change it as we saw fit. We could even have different coding systems for different parts of the Trust, all sorts of things. All interesting things to muse on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 of useR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=74/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 19:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=74/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I said I was going to blog at least one thing I learned at the conference each day, today I’ve learned about 50 million things (yesterday was tutorials so I learned two things well; seen 20 presentations today, posters later).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be honest I think this post is going to be more use to me in remembering everything than it will be to anyone else, but I’ll try to do it properly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>useR conference update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=61/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 19:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=61/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.warwick.ac.uk/statsdept/user-2011/&#34;&gt;useR! conference&lt;/a&gt; so I’ll be blogging every day with at least one thing that I learned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first thing, which I think I half-knew and had also half-learned from bitter experience, is that all the R experts seem to use Linux, Ubuntu in the case of the two people who ran the tutorials I attended today. I already dual-boot Windows and Linux and I think over time I’m going to reduce Windows to the operating system on which I play games and check my work email (which I can only get to run on Windows due to security software requirements).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect the way my mortgage is paid off?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=46/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 16:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a baby on the way my wife and I have become very interested in the interest rate on our mortgage, and how it might go up or down, and how that will affect whether we overpay to build up some equity, etc. etc. etc. As you will know if you’ve ever thought about your mortgage payments, it’s all quite complicated and difficult to think about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a bit of fun I thought I would produce a graph which summarises the value of the mortgage over time as well as the proportion of the money which is spent on capital and interest payments. The repayment is fixed for a given value of interest, so a stacked barchart will have a fixed height, with a different proportion of the bar coming from capital and interest payments over time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New book- The visual display of quantitative information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=40/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 15:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=40/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took delivery of a new book today, Tufte’s Visual Display of Quantitative Information. Obviously it’s a classic but I had no idea what a beautiful book it is. Camera doesn’t do it justice:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/photo2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://chrisbeeley.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/photo2.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;The Visual Display of Quantitative Information&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full of wonderful illustrations from throughout the ages as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll cover this and some of my favourite books past and present in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun with wordclouds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 15:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As always, I’m late to this party, and wordclouds have come under fire in recent times, e.g. here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drewconway.com/zia/?p=2624&#34;&gt;drewconway.com&lt;/a&gt;. From my point of view they’re eye-catching, and I hope that by putting them up on a website or in a report they might cause people to linger and look in more detail at other pieces of data and visualisation. That’s all I’m going to say for now, I’m sure I’ll talk again about what’s attractive to data scientists and statisticians and what’s attractive to the general public, but let’s leave it for now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The patient survey: past, present and future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 14:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within my organisation we have something known as the Service User and Carer Experience Survey, often abbreviated to the SUCE, or in more natural spoken English, the patient survey. It’s a chance for the users of our services to tell us about our services and includes Likert-type “ticky box” questions about specific aspects of care as well as an open section in which they can give an area for improvement as well as something they like about the service. Results are published quarterly and reporting represents a major challenge- we report over about 100 teams, all organised into larger directorates and divisions, with each category having its own type of report. I’ve been involved right from the start and the process goes nicely from a How-Not-To-Do-It guide to a How-To guide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 12:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the many excellent blogs about research, statistics, and computing I have finally decided to set up my own. My work for Nottinghamshire Healthcare NHS Trust and the Institute of Mental Health comprises advice and consultancy, research and evaluation, and data visualisation. I like to use R for my statistics, and have recently started making reproducible research using Sweave and odfWeave. Over time I have found I need to write more and more code and I am studying Java in October to help me on the way to being a proper programmer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
