<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on not-much demo</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on not-much demo</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 13:55:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The shinyverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/post/2018-10-02-the-shinyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 13:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/post/2018-10-02-the-shinyverse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty sure I’ve made up the word shinyverse, to refer to all the packages that either use or complement Shiny. This is a non-exhaustive list of shinyverse packages, mainly for my benefit when I inevitably forget, but if it’s useful for you too then that’s good too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/shiny.semantic/index.html&#34;&gt;shiny.semantic&lt;/a&gt; adds support for the Semantic UI library to Shiny. Useful if you want your Shiny apps to look a bit different or there’s something in the library that you need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filling in non missing elements by row (Survey Monkey masterclass)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/post/2018-10-02-filling-in-non-missing-elements-by-row-survey-monkey-masterclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/post/2018-10-02-filling-in-non-missing-elements-by-row-survey-monkey-masterclass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There must be other people out there doing this, so I’ll share this neat thing I found today. Quite often, you’ll have a dataset that has a lot of columns, only one of which will have something in it for each row. Survey Monkey, in particular, produces these kinds of sheets if you use branching logic. So if you work in one bit of the Trust, your team name will be found in one column, but if you branched elsewhere in the survey because you work somewhere else, it is in another column. Lots of columns, but each individual has only one non-missing element in each (because they only work in one place and only see that question once).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
