<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patient Survey on Chris Beeley&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/tags/patient-survey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patient Survey on Chris Beeley&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 06:22:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/tags/patient-survey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simulating data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 06:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to publish as much of my work as I can on the internet, where the people who own the data agree (my little bit of the website is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.institutemh.org.uk/-about-us-/our-evaluation-service&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) but very often I can’t publish the data because of issues with ongoing projects, other publications, various levels of confidentiality of data, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I’ve decided to try to simulate the data whenever there is an issue with publication. It’s very easy and it’s an excellent way for me to be able to show people my work without any of the issues that come from showing real data. The code is below, it comes in two parts for the first set of variables because we fiddled with the questionnaire a bit after Time 8 in the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun with wordclouds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 15:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As always, I’m late to this party, and wordclouds have come under fire in recent times, e.g. here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drewconway.com/zia/?p=2624&#34;&gt;drewconway.com&lt;/a&gt;. From my point of view they’re eye-catching, and I hope that by putting them up on a website or in a report they might cause people to linger and look in more detail at other pieces of data and visualisation. That’s all I’m going to say for now, I’m sure I’ll talk again about what’s attractive to data scientists and statisticians and what’s attractive to the general public, but let’s leave it for now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The patient survey: past, present and future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 14:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chris_beeley_blog/?p=8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within my organisation we have something known as the Service User and Carer Experience Survey, often abbreviated to the SUCE, or in more natural spoken English, the patient survey. It’s a chance for the users of our services to tell us about our services and includes Likert-type “ticky box” questions about specific aspects of care as well as an open section in which they can give an area for improvement as well as something they like about the service. Results are published quarterly and reporting represents a major challenge- we report over about 100 teams, all organised into larger directorates and divisions, with each category having its own type of report. I’ve been involved right from the start and the process goes nicely from a How-Not-To-Do-It guide to a How-To guide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
